迈克
Mike!
你到底在干什么
What the hell are you doing?
这叫开车  马库斯
It's called driving, Marcus.
慢一点
Slow down!
什么  4分钟吗  立马加速
What? Four minutes? Speed up.
所以你想让我在加速的同时慢一点吗
So you want me to speed up and slow down at the same time?
向南往柯林斯走
Moving southbound on Collins.
-快速接近22街  -收到
- Fast approaching 22 Street. - Copy that.
空中支援已看到目标
Air support has a visual.
迈克
Mike!
我要吐了
I'm about to throw up.
你最好  千万别吐
Oh, you bett... The hell not.
这可是手工缝制的皮革  你最好咽下去
That is hand-stitched leather. You better drink it.
已封锁第6街
Blocking off 6th Street.
你该在那转弯的  迈克
That was your turn, Mike!
该死  你是导航员  好吗
Damn it! Look, you are the navigator, okay?
这就是为什么你坐在副驾上
That's why you're sitting in that seat.
你眼镜在哪里  你该把眼镜戴起来
Where are your glasses? You need to put your glasses on.
我不需要眼镜
I don't need glasses.
马库斯  你什么都看不清
Marcus, you can't see shit.
迈克  迈克  迈克
Oh, sh... Mike. Mike. Mike.
-放松  -迈克  公交车
- Relax. Relax! - Mike. Bus, bus, bus.
抱歉  有钱白人
Sorry, rich white people.
我们不只是黑人  我们还是警察
We're not just black, we're cops too.
我们过会再自己靠边停车
We'll pull ourselves over later.
蝙蝠侠战车都没我这宝贝车表现好
Even the Batmobile don't hold the road like this bitch.
赶紧让我下车
Get me the fuck out of this car.
该死
Oh, shit.
拜托  老兄
Come on, man.
你可以拿去修补一下
You can get that buffed out.
不  是你拿去修补一下
No. You can get that buffed out.
-迈阿密警察  让一下  -借过
- Miami PD. Make a hole. - Coming through.
-让一让  迈阿密警察  -迈阿密警察
- Make a hole. Miami PD. - Miami PD.
快  快
Go! Go!
抱歉
Sorry.
爸比
Daddy!
大兄弟
Joker.
你是爷爷了
You a pop-pop.
绝地战警3
疾速追击
-宝贝  看看他  -是啊
- Oh, baby, look at him. - Yeah.
毫无疑问  眼睛真像
No doubt. It's in the eyes.
还有耳朵
And the ears.
还有名字
And the name.
马库斯·迈尔斯·伯内特
Marcus Miles Burnett.
-但那是我的名字  -也是他的
- But that's my name. - His name too.
我们决定以你的名字命名
We decided to name after you.
是雷吉的主意
It was Reggie's idea.
感觉是表达尊敬的最好方式  长官
Thought it would be a very respectful gesture, sir.
-希望您能同意  -挺好的
- I hope you approve. - That's cool.
但你还是得给我家宝贝女儿
But you still need to make a honest woman
一个难忘的婚礼
out of my baby girl there.
迈克叔叔  准备好抱娃了吗
Uncle Mike, ready to hold the baby?
不不  迈克叔叔可不想接手
Oh, mm-mm. No. Uncle Mike don't want to catch that.
别这样  行吗  就是这德行
Uh-uh, okay? That's that shit.
-别啊  迈克  -打住
- No, Mike. - Stop.
看看宝宝
Look at the baby.
给我立马打住  我认真的
Stop it right now. Seriously.
-看看宝宝啊  -好吧  知道不
- Look at the baby. - Okay, you know what?
你把自己情绪收拾好  我在外边等你
I'll be outside when you get your shit together.
迈克
Mike.
-是宝宝  -没事的
- The baby. - Oh, it's okay.
墨西哥  圣玛丽亚伊克斯科特监狱
赶紧的 女人们
你们这些废物
快一点
阿莉塔斯
Aretas.
搞什么鬼
拦住刚刚的救护车
妈妈
Mama.
我的孩子
墨西哥城
别为了他的死而悲伤
你父亲的灵魂已从
囚禁他的桎梏中解脱
这是你爸爸死前最后的礼物
你已成人 终于准备好完成未竟之业了
你一定要为家族重新带来荣耀和尊重
你父亲在被抓之前藏了数百万美元
这里存着能找到他们的坐标
我们会拿回本属于我们的
有了这笔钱 我们就能报仇了
毁了我们家族的人
会尝到被猎杀的滋味
让他最后一个死
过来  马库斯  过来
Come here, Marcus. Come here.
我们欢聚在此
We're here to celebrate
庆祝我们其中一员
and to raise a glass to one of our own.
我衷心地希望  有一天
And I sincerely hope that someday
继承了你名字的小宝贝
your namesake follows in the footsteps
能追随这个老祖父的脚步
of his old-ass grandpa...
保护并服务我们美丽的城市
...to protect and serve our fair city.
敬马库斯
To Marcus.
To Marcus!
愿马库斯·伯内特之名
May the name Marcus Burnett
能够震慑那些王八蛋的思想和灵魂
strike fear into the hearts and minds of assholes
经年不衰
for years to come.
谢谢大家  谢谢
Thank y'all. Thank... Thank you all.
迈克和我
Mike and I,
我们搭档了25年守护这些街道
we're going on 25 years of working these streets.
我相信  我们的努力是有成效的
And I like to think we made a difference.
你们是最棒的
You all are the best.
我也感谢你们  真的很荣幸
And I thank you. It's been a real honor.
马库斯
Marcus!
马库斯  马库斯  马库斯
Marcus! Marcus! Marcus!
迈阿密湾
你爸把钱埋得挺深呢
Daddy buried that cash deep, huh?
要是这些是空的  你还是欠我们钱
If these are empty, you're still gonna owe.
我的妈呀
Whoa! Mamma mia!
把宝藏埋在海里
Buried treasure in the ocean.
我听到过流言  但是
I heard the stories, pero coño...
应该足够支付我们谈好的材料了
Should cover the cost of the materials we discussed.
还多了一些
And then some.
这些是你能拿走的
This is what you get to keep.
你说什么
What'd you say?
我们谈好的
We had a deal.
我再重新谈一次
I'm renegotiating.
一不小心
Whoops.
过来
Come here.
看着我
Look at me.
我从来都不重新谈判
I don't renegotiate.
我的家族要重新拿回这个城市的管理权
My family's taking back management of this town.
我们需要雇一些忠诚的手下
We're gonna need some, uh, loyal employees.
谁想要份工作
Who wants a job?
你这牙科保险怎么样
So how's your dental?
再说一遍
Say that again.
冷静
你给自己赢得了加薪
You give yourselves a raise.
从那堆开始
You start with that pile right there.
-好吗  -好
- Okay? - Okay.
从现在开始你为我工作
You work for me now.
让你的人都乖乖听话
Get your people to fall in line,
别挡我的路  我就不会杀你
stay out of my fucking way, and I won't kill you.
过来  小伙子们  把钱都整理好
Vamos, muchacho, get this money ¡Dale!
快来
Vamos.
快啊
¡Vamos!
妈妈
Mama.
阿曼多
Armando.
是我们的了
动作挺快
我们也有了新的行动基地
你在那边待了太长时间
听起来都像美国佬了
我不干了  迈克
I'm done, Mike.
又来了
Oh, here we go again.
不  这次不一样
No, this time it's different.
当我看着小宝宝的眼睛时
When I looked into that little baby's eyes,
有点东西变了
something changed.
我想花时间
I want to spend my days
看着那孩子长大
watching that little boy grow.
老兄  特蕾莎才不想你坐在家里变胖
Man, Theresa does not want your ass sitting at home,
无所事事  到处搞破坏
getting fat and breaking shit.
迈克  我们已经活了大半辈子了
You know, Mike, we got more time behind us than in front.
是时候做出改变了  真的
It's time to make some changes, for real.
你可别忽悠我  我过的日子是最棒的
You can mess me with that. I'm living my best life.
你已经开始染胡子了  迈克
You're dyeing your goatee, Mike.
-什么  -你染胡子了
- What? - You're dyeing your goatee.
我才没有染胡子
I am not dyeing my goatee.
那颜色是午夜豆蔻  我认出来了
That's Midnight Cocoa Bean. I recognize that.
马库斯  少来
Marcus, go ahead with that shit.
那不是午夜豆蔻吗
That ain't Midnight Cocoa...?
-摸别的去  -那我问问你
- Go ahead somewhere. - Let me ask you something.
你希望你的遗产只是
You want your legacy to be
紧身T恤和死亡统计加1吗
muscle shirts and a body count?
你不知道家庭最重要吗
Don't you know family is all that matters?
嘿  祖父
Hey, granddaddy!
-丽塔  -不  不  是爷爷
-Rita. - Oh, no. Pop-pop.
他愿意被叫爷爷
He's going with Pop-pop.
-爷爷  -对
- Pop-pop? - Yeah.
有照片吗  爷爷
Got pics, Pop-pop?
-你知道我有  -让我看看
- Oh, you know I do, right? - Let's see.
给你
There you go.
我的天  这耳朵
Oh, my God, the ears!
是的  我的孙子  那是我孙子
Yeah, my grandbaby. That's my grandbaby.
爱死他了
I love him.
也恭喜你  警官
And congrats to you, lieutenant.
我听说霍华德钦点你去了弹丸小队
I hear Howard tapped you to head up AMMO.
恭喜啊
Wow, congrats.
弹丸小队是什么
What's AMMO?
迈阿密市区高级行动部
Advanced Miami Metro Operations.
使用新型战略和调查方法
A small team trained in new tactics
训练的一个小队
and investigative methods.
会逐一代替我们这些老家伙
Gonna replace us old dogs.
或者教他们些新的技巧
Or teach them some new tricks.
说真的  马库斯  太为你高兴了
For real, Marcus. So happy for you.
谢谢
Thank you.
嘿  大家伙
Hey, guys!
所有人都在呢
Hey! Everyone's here.
你怎么样
How are you?
蠢货
Dumbass.
-干嘛  -她太适合你了
- What? -She is perfect for you.
聪明绝顶
Smart as hell.
自信  有雄心
Confident. Ambitious.
她才不是合适我的那个人
She just wasn't the one for me.
是吗  那你要怎样
All right? What is for you?
一个人孤独终老吗
Dying all alone and sad as shit?
你就是嫉妒
You just jealous.
你结婚多久了  二十年了吗
How long you been married? Twenty years?
-二十六年了  -说真话
- Twenty-six. - Tell the truth.
你上次做爱是什么时候了
When's the last time you had sex?
-关你屁事  -就是说啊
- None of your damn business. - Exactly.
你要错过多少超棒的女人
How many great women are you gonna let go? Heh.
虽然说你的确有很多人爱
I mean, you get a lot of loving,
但你有真的爱过吗
but have you ever really been in love?
当然  我也坠入过爱河
Of course. I mean, yeah, I was... I was in love.
有一次
One time.
在很久很久以前
A long, long time ago.
你从来没和我说过
You never told me.
老哥  我不用什么都和你说的
Nigga, I don't tell you all my business.
你只需要知道
Look, all you need to know
我就算100岁了也不会停止追捕罪犯的
is that I'll be running down criminals till I'm 100.
兄弟  在医院的那件事后
You the last brother that needs to be talking
最没有资格和我说追捕的就是你了
about running down anyone after the hospital.
医院  你在说什么
The hospital? What you talking about?
在医院时候发生了什么
What happened at the hospital?
跑去医院看刚出生的小马库斯
Running to see baby Marcus.
我给你吃了我的屁
I dusted your ass.
你全程都在看着我的翘臀  迈克
You spent that run staring at my one good ass-cheek, Mike.
你在说你其实跑得比我快吗
You're saying that you actually outran me?
你在跑步比赛中击败了我吗
You beat me in a footrace?
事实胜于雄辩
It's been said.
才不是呢
Oh, hell, no.
没什么比一个老人回忆过去更让人悲伤了
Nothing sadder than old men revisiting the past.
不准做拉伸
Whoa, hey, no stretching.
做拉伸是在作弊
Stretching is cheating.
你赌谁赢  老大
Hey, who you got, Cap?
我赌50你们绝对韧带撕裂
I got 50 on a torn ACL.
我可不白跑
I ain't running for free.
-赌点什么吧  -我赢了  我们就休息
- What's the bet? - I win, we lay it down.
我们上交辞职报告然后退休
We turn in our papers and we retire.
好的  那要是我赢了
All right, well, when I win,
你别再说这些关于退休的蠢话
you stop all this foolish retirement talk.
我们继续风驰电掣  直到车轮散架
We ride this thing till the wheels fall off.
坏男孩一辈子
Bad boys for life.
坏男孩已经不是真正的男孩了
Uh, bad boys ain't really boys anymore.
老大  让救护车在旁边待命
Hey, Cap, just have the ambo on standby.
老男孩会需要输液和输氧
Old boy gonna need fluids and oxygen.
-是他需要  老大  是他  -行了
-That's him, Cap. That's him. - Okay.
各就各位  预备  跑
On your mark, get set, go!
-冲啊马库斯  你可以的  -你在哪呢
- Go, Marcus! You got this! - Where you at?
-你能赢的  调整呼吸  -你在哪呢
- You got this! Breathe! - Uh-oh, where you at?
加油宝贝
Come on, baby!
呼吸  宝贝  调整呼吸  冲啊
Breathe, baby, breathe! Go!
你在哪呢宝贝
Where you at, baby?!
迈克
Mike!
迈克  迈克  该死  快来人帮帮我
Mike. Mike! Oh, shit! Get some help!
我这有一个警官倒地
I got an officer down.
我们在海洋道700街区
We're on Ocean Drive, 700 block.
-坚持住  -是枪伤
- Hold on. - Gunshot...
-该死  -发生什么了
- Oh, shit. - What happened?
-快来点人帮忙  -是谁干的
- Just get... Get some help! - Who did this?!
到底是哪个王八蛋干的
Who the fuck did this?!
骑着一辆摩托车
Driving a motorcycle...
拜托  别这样
Come on. Don't do this.
迈克  坚持住  加油
Mike, stay with us. Come on.
快来辆救护车
Get an ambulance!
拜托  迈克  加油
Come on, Mike. Come on. Hey, hey, hey.
他在联系救护车了
Phone... I got him on the phone.
你会没事的  你一定能挺过去的
You gonna be all right. You gonna make it through this.
拜托  兄弟  别离开我们  兄弟
Come on, man. Stay with us, man.
拜托  迈克  我就在这
Come on, Mike. I'm right here.
亲爱的上帝
Dear God...
是我  马库斯
it's me, Marcus.
最近很多事都多亏有您保佑
You blessed me with a lot of stuff lately.
我知道我有段时间没来教堂了
I know I haven't been to church in a while.
上次来可能是复活节
Probably Easter.
但说老实话
But I ain't gonna lie,
我的确没怎么太上心
I wasn't paying attention.
但我还没有失去信仰
I haven't lost faith.
只是
It's just...
我对那些我们不得不做的事情感到很羞愧
I was ashamed at some of the stuff we had to do.
我知道圣经说"汝不可杀人"
I know "thou shall not kill,"
但那些都是坏家伙  全都是
but they were bad guys, all of them.
迈克几乎没有自己的生活
You know, Mike hardly had a life yet.
没有妻子  没有孩子
No wife, no kids.
如果可以的话  请你在心里
If you could just please find it in your heart
再给他一次机会  我的主
to give him one more chance, man.
他真的是我最好的朋友
Straight up, he's my best friend.
我的兄弟
My brother.
如果你能饶恕他
If you just spare him,
我向你发誓
I swear to you,
我再也不会在这个世界上使用暴力
I will put no more violence in this world.
一起飞车射击导致
A drive-by shooting
一位著名迈阿密老警官生命垂危
has a famed Miami-Dade police officer fighting for his life.
目击者说听到了枪声
Witnesses report hearing shots
和一辆从现场溜走的全黑的机车
and a blacked-out bike fleeing the scene.
迈克·劳瑞警探的生命仍处于危险中
Detective Mike Lowrey remains in critical...
伙计们  给老大汇报一下案子目前的进展
Guys, let's run Cap through what we got on the case.
凯莉  汇报一下弹道分析
Kelly, run us through ballistics.
射中劳瑞警官的是SS190型穿甲弹
So the slugs in Officer Lowrey were SS190.
出自赫斯塔尔P90冲锋枪
P90 fires that caliber, the Herstal.
但这些子弹是5.7乘28毫米口径消声弹
But these were subsonic 5.7-by-28s,
定制型的
custom rounds.
我想知道谁生产了这些子弹
I wanna know who made those bullets.
我们正在看4Chan
We are watching 4chan
国外的综合讨论区
并把市场上的卖家
and cross-referencing players in the market
和联邦犯罪数据库做交叉对比
with the feds' red lines.
迈克就像我的儿子
Mike's like a son to me.
给我找到这个混蛋
I want this asshole.
对我而言这也是私人恩怨
This is personal for me too.
让我们把所有微小的线索拼凑起来  好吗
Let's bring every single thing we got, all right?
放心吧
You got it.
墨西哥城
我说得很清楚 劳瑞最后一个死
我才是动手的人
我懂得怎么搞定事情 好吧
你已经训练了我一辈子了
那个警察是个威胁 其他人都不算什么
你到底听不听我的命令
我想要他看着其他人死
你就负责照做
不要再违背我的命令
检察官罗德里戈·瓦尔加
搜索
迈阿密最强硬的检察官
退休地方检察官罗德里戈·瓦加斯
Retired DA Rodrigo Vargas
于今日下午被枪杀
was gunned down this afternoon.
杰克·韦伯博士  法医调查员
缉毒局今天傍晚为杰克·韦伯默哀
The DEA is mourning Jack Weber this evening,
他作为法医调查员
a 20-year forensic investigator
警方怀疑
近期凶杀案
有联系
在迈阿密工作了二十年
for the agency in Miami.
法官莱昂·索伦森
找到你了
There you are.
发生了另一起处决式的谋杀
In yet another execution-style homicide...
莱昂·索伦森法官周三晚些时候
Judge Leon Sorenson was shot
在他的院子外被射杀
outside his courthouse late Wednesday.
午夜豆蔻
执法之战仍在继续
The war on law enforcement continues.
另外三起针对执法部门人员的谋杀
Three other law enforcement personnel
都与本案有联系
have been killed that could be linked to our case.
这是一场针对法律的较量
It's a war on the goddamn law.
和射杀迈克的是同一个枪手
All the same shooter as Mike.
-你怎么发现的  -交通摄像头  目击证人
- Connected how? - Traffic cams, witnesses,
和轮胎痕迹都指向
tire treads all put the same
同一辆现场出现过的黑色摩托车
blacked-out bike at the scene.
六个月后
感谢大家今天的到来
We want to thank you for joining us today.
对于这个家庭来说意义重大
It means a lot to the family.
现在我宣布你们结为夫妻了
And I now pronounce you man and wife.
你可以吻新娘了
You may kiss the bride.
我真的不能再这样哭了
I really gotta stop crying like this.
你们做得很棒
Hey, you guys are great.
女士们先生们  到了举杯致辞的时候了
Ladies and gentlemen, it's time for our first toast.
让我们有请迈克·劳瑞警官
I'm going to bring up Officer Mike Lowrey,
即是亲爱的迈克大叔
affectionately known as Uncle Mike.
首先  雷吉
First off, Reggie,
我很惊讶你居然还在这里
I am shocked that you are even still here.
我记得你第一次和梅根约会的时候
I remember your first date with Megan,
说真的
and trust me,
我和马库斯尽我们所能
me and Marcus did everything we could possibly do
来确保你不会再出现
to make sure you never came back.
但我要告诉你  爱情是艰难的
But I'm telling you, love is hard.
你们的关系会受到考验
And your relationship will be tested.
你父亲和我一起经历了风风雨雨
And your father and I have weathered storm after storm.
我们有句在最黑暗的时候
And we have a mantra that we say to each other
对彼此说的口号
in our darkest days,
而这口号总是能将我们凝聚在一起
and it always seems to bring us back together.
雷吉  梅根  我想把它分享给你们
And, Reggie, Megan, I would like to share it with you.
我们一起风驰电掣
We ride together,
我们一起走到尽头
we die together.
坏男孩一辈子
Bad boys for life!
不
No.
-不什么  -你知道的
- No, what? - You know what.
我听到你活下来的那一刻
The minute I heard you were still breathing,
我就知道你要搞事
I've been waiting for this shit to hit the fan.
看着我迈克  我说不
Look at me, Mike. No.
你还不知道我要说什么
You don't know what I'm gonna say.
我了解你  我知道你要说什么
I know you. I know what you're gonna say.
这事弹丸小队负责
AMMO's got this.
弹丸小队吗
AMMO?
拜托  老大  弹丸小队吗  恕我直言
Come on, Cap. AMMO? With all due respect,
弹丸小队只是一个有枪的
AMMO is a high school musical...
高中男生乐队  他们什么都搞不定
boy band with guns. They don't even have shit.
你怎么知道他们行不行  他们能行
How do you know what they have or don't have? They have!
-那他们能干什么  -他们有点东西
- What do they have? - They have.
有什么
What?
从你身上挖出来的子弹
The bullets they carved out of you,
它们来自定制的赫斯塔尔P90冲锋枪
they were custom rounds for the P90 Herstal.
弹丸小队会找到提供子弹给枪手的供应商
AMMO's gonna find the dealer that supplied your shooter
怎么找
How?
最先进的办案科技和方式  这就是答案
State-of-the-art police work, that's how.
-老大  听我说  -够了
- Cap, look... - All right.
-长官  -长官
- Sir. - Sir?
你已经急切到这程度了
You are desperate.
但我不能
But I can't.
迈克  我不能让你调查你自己的案子
Mike, I can't let you investigate your own case.
好吧  那让我调查瓦嘉斯的案子
All right. Let me investigate the Vargas case.
不  我可不想让内务部
No. The last thing I need is having IAD shoving a Hubble
把我查个底朝天
telescope up my ass for a full-on colonoscopy.
-你知道规定的  -去他妈的规定  老大
- You know the rules. - Fuck the rules, Cap.
拜托  让我和马库斯调查这个案子
Come on. Put me and Marcus on this shit.
你和你的搭档聊过了吗
Have you talked to your partner?
你退休了吗
You retired?
这是我女儿的婚礼
It's my daughter's wedding.
你一定要现在说这些吗
Do we have to do this right now?
没错
Uh, yeah.
-我和你说了我要退休  -什么
- I told you I was retiring. - Wha...? What?
等等  我们赛跑了  然后你输了
Wait, nah, hold up. We raced, you lost.
现在你反悔了吗  说好的一辈子坏男孩呢
Now you reneging? What happened to bad boys for life?
是的  一辈子  这已经结束了
Yeah, for life. It's off.
你死了
You died.
什么  你到底在说什么
What? The hell are you talking about?
你的心跳都停止了  迈克  三次
You coded out, Mike, three times.
马库斯  听我说
Marcus, look,
这个混蛋从我这偷走了一些东西
this motherfucker stole something from me
我要把它们夺回来
and I need it back.
他从你那拿走了什么  迈克
What did he take from you, Mike?
你还在这里
You're still here.
他只是夺走了你的传奇
All he took from you was the legend,
"刀枪不入的迈克"
"Bulletproof Mike."
但是我看见你躺在地上流血
But I saw you on the ground bleeding.
你也只是个凡人  和我们一样
You're human, just like the rest of us.
这混蛋同样也是个凡人
Yeah, his ass bleeds too.
我告诉你  迈克
Heh, I'm telling you, Mike.
你只要出去报仇
You go out there for vengeance,
有人会因你丢掉性命
you gonna get someone killed.
我们非得报这个仇不可
Oh, we definitely bringing some smoke.
那混蛋在我身上留了几个枪眼
That fool put holes in me!
那只会让你的内心充满仇恨  迈克
And you're filling them with hate, Mike.
听着  你需要重新想一下你的因果报应
Look, you need to start thinking about your karma, man.
这是一个信号
This was a sign.
一个信号  是啊  一个硬起来的信号
A sign, yeah. A sign to turn up.
难道我应该忍气吞声
I'm supposed to bow down?
放那个混蛋一马
Give this bitch a pass?
"硬起来"  你多大  20岁吗
"Turn up"? What are you, 20?
你需要消停一下了
You need to turn that shit off.
知道吗  迈克
You know, Mike, heh...
在你住院的的时候
Rita called me every day
丽塔每天都给我打电话
you were in the hospital.
有些东西一直在等你  未来
There's something still there, a future.
我的未来就是逮捕这个狗娘养的混蛋
My future is hunting this motherfucker.
好吧  那至少不是我的
Well, it's not mine.
好吧  那我就直说了
All right. So let me get this straight.
有人在街上想要置我于死地
So somebody get to dump my ass out in the street
然后你却不准备做任何事
and you ain't gonna do shit?
你就这么不干了
You just gonna quit?
你怎么敢这么说  伙计
How dare you, man?
是我一直守在你的床边
I sat by your bedside.
是我帮你把口水擦干净  迈克
I wiped the drool off your chin, Mike.
你不能这样不尊重我
Don't disrespect me like that
因为你什么都不知道
because you don't know.
好  好  好  兄弟
All right, all right. All right, man.
听着  马库斯
Look, Marcus,
我拜托你
I'm asking you.
我求你了  兄弟
I'm begging you, man.
我需要报仇
I need this.
坏男孩组合
Bad boys...
最后一次
one last time.
不行  迈克
No, Mike.
不行
No.
已故毒枭曾是墨西哥的英雄
这些都是为了你 爸爸
妈妈
Mama.
他还没有死
这不就是你想要的吗
只有在他受过和我们一样的折磨以后
死神才允许他死
在得到我的允许之前不要杀他
我会让他生不如死的
"刀枪不入"神警终于康复
正在上传
给你的粉丝一点小惊喜
迈阿密警察遭枪击现场视频
真他妈一团糟呢\h\h笑死
悲剧\h\h同情他的家里人
难以置信
我操 枪法真好
这他妈是什么鬼
迈阿密警察遭枪击现场视频
当迈阿密警官遭枪击的视频
Video of a shooting of a Miami detective
被发布到网上  几小时内便引起强烈反向
has surfaced online, going viral in a matter of hours.
这个视频一开始被发布在暗网
The video first appeared on the darknet
并且很快就被传到各大主流媒体平台
and soon spread to mainstream social media.
专家认为这是枪手自己所为
Authorities believe the shooter uploaded the video himself.
太慢了
Too slow.
你退步了
You're slipping.
我还有钥匙
Still had the key.
什么事
What's up?
霍华德告诉我你想参与这案子
Howard told me you wanted back in.
这不可能
Obviously, that can't happen.
谁说的
Says who?
迈克尔
Micheal
你受了枪伤
you got shot.
是啊  大家不断提醒我这件事
Yeah, people keep reminding me of that.
那你觉得为什么会这样
Well, why do you think that is? Huh?
你开始对我进行心理分析了
Oh, you shrinking me now.
当你不想面对事实的时候  你就这样说
You say that when you don't wanna get real.
不  当你对我心理分析的时候我才这么说
No, I always say that when you start shrinking me.
弹丸小队专门处理这类案件
Hey, this is the type of case that AMMO was built for.
你只需要信任我即可
You just have to trust me, that's all.
得了吧  说什么呢
Oh, come on. What?
为什么你总是这么说
Why you always go there?
这和信任没有任何关系
This don't have nothing to do with me trusting you or not.
-没有吗  -没有
- Oh, no? - No.
那你痊愈了吗
Are you even healed?
-是啊  我很好  -是吗
- Yeah, I'm fine. Yeah. - Yeah?
-你确定你很好吗  -该死  丽塔
- You sure you're fine? - Oh, shit. Rita.
-你确定你很好吗  -丽塔  停下来
- You sure you're fine? - Hey. Rita. Stop. Rita.
看清楚你在和谁说大话
This is me you're trying to bullshit.
如果你参加
If you get involved,
你绝对会犯下你无法挽回的错误
you're gonna make mistakes you can't take back.
只有死亡才能将我们分离[西语]
Hasta el fuego.
"只有死亡才能让我们分离"
"Hasta el fuego."
这到底是什么意思  你从哪学的
What does that mean? Where'd you get that?
要死一起死
Until you burn? Until you die?
你要是足够了解我就不要劝我退出
You know me well enough to know not to ask me to quit.
正因为我了解你  我才劝你
It's because I know you, I'm asking.
因为我关心你
Because I care about you.
作为你的朋友
As a friend.
让我们来处理这件事
Let us handle this.
该死  阿莱莎  把声音调小一点
Shit. Alexa, turn down the volume.
马库斯
Ah! Marcus!
快给我出去
You need to get out of the house!
抱歉  宝贝
Sorry, baby.
非常抱歉
So sorry.
让我们来个水疗日如何
How about a spa day?
-这是曼尼的车吗  -是的
- Is that Manny's car? -Yeah.
-曼尼在哪  -他在后面
- Where's Manny? - He's in the back.
该死  迈克·劳瑞  你来这做什么
Oh, shit. Mike Lowrey. What are you doing here, man?
你神出鬼没  伙计
You look like a ghost, man.
知道吗  他们都说你死了  我操
You know they say you're dead, fuckboy.
我给你看个东西
I gotta show you something.
道上都在说
The streets is talking.
你不适合当警察了
That cop shit ain't working for you.
来跟我一块在曼尼的肋排店工作吧
Come work for me at Manny's Prime Rib.
看  你在这里被枪击
See, look, you get dropped right here.
然后你猜怎么着
And guess what.
你火遍全世界
You're trending worldwide.
我的手
Ow! My fucking hand, man!
你可不按套路出牌  伙计
Yo, this ain't no fucking cop shit, man!
你不能剥夺我说话的权力
What happened about reading my rights?
程序不应该这样走的
This is not how it's supposed to go.
你应该先问我问题
You're supposed to ask me questions,
然后我说  "滚你丫的"
and then I tell you, "Go fuck yourself!"
你在干什么
What the fuck, man?
我操
Fuck! Ow!
老子的玉手
My fucking hand, man.
定制赫斯塔尔P90冲锋枪  谁生产的
P90 Herstals, custom, who's making them?
迈克  我早就不干了
Mike, I'm not in the game no more.
是吗  这样啊  我的错
Oh, nah? Okay. My bad.
迈克  你他妈冷静一下
Ah! Mike, Mike, fucking chill, man.
迈阿密这么多素食主义者
So all these vegans in Miami,
我会相信你门口停着的那辆跑车
and you want me to believe that that hot rod
是你卖肉排攒出来的吗
outside comes from selling pork chops?
我在肋排店工作  我是一个顾家的人
I work at Manny's. I'm a family man,
-我勤勤恳恳  -是吗  好的
- and I'm a hardworking man. - Oh. I got you...
该死  该死
Oh, shit. Oh, man.
你是不是把猪油抹到我的西装上了
Did you just get pig fat on my suit?
抱歉  迈克
Sorry, Mike.
抱歉
Sorry.
不要  是布克·格拉西
No! Booker Grassie!
这是你找的人  布克·格拉西
That's the name! Booker Grassie!
这是你找的人  伙计
That's the name, man!
迈克  别走  迈克
Yo, Mike! Mike! Yo, Mike!
手铐  伙计
The handcuffs, man!
布克·格拉西  迈阿密唯一的军火商
Booker Grassie. Only arms dealer in Miami
专门生产定制赫斯塔尔P90冲锋枪
customizing for the P90 Herstal.
-我跟你说过什么  -我知道
- What'd I tell you? - I know.
我不该调查自己的案子  我知道规矩的
I'm not supposed to investigate my own case. I know the rules.
但这混蛋把枪击我的视频发到网上
But this fool posted a video of him trying to kill me.
我看见了
I saw it.
我要么以私刑的方式追捕他
I can go after him vigilante style,
要么你让我加入
or you can bring me in.
要么我朝你开一枪
Or I could shoot you myself.
我靠
Fuck me!
靠  靠  靠
Oh, fuck, fuck, fuck!
如果
If...
我让你以顾问的身份加入
...I bring you in, to consult,
但你要是给我搞砸了
and you go cowboy on me,
你得知道我要承担的后果
I need you to comprehend the level-five shitstorm
可是炼狱级别的
I will be drowning in.
没有奖章
No gold-plated watch.
没有退休薪金
No cop retirement village.
我可是冒着很大风险的
I'm sticking myself out on a skinny limb!
就好比暴风雪里的一根小树枝
Scratch that. A twig in an ice storm!
我站在那树枝边缘  快"腰腰欲坠"了
Me, on the edge, "tithering."
你是说  摇摇欲坠吗
You mean, teetering?
我就是这么说的
That's what I said!
还有想象我是个胖子
And picture me very fat!
我能想象得到那个画面  老大
Uh, think I got the image, Cap.
他来这做什么
What is he doing here?
他来给你们帮忙
He's gonna be helping out.
-我不需要他  -我可不想和她工作
- I don't want him. - I'm not working with her.
你们谁也不和谁工作  他只是顾问
He's not. You're not. He's consulting.
还是你们负责
It's your show.
-老大  别这样  -等一下
- Captain, come on. - Wait.
我知道你们俩有过一腿
I know you guys got history together,
-所以我们不要带有个人情感  -个人情感
- so let's not make it personal. - Personal?
这里现在就只有我在保持职业素养
I'm the only one being professional.
这不是在跟你商量
This is not détente.
我只是在告诉你我的决定
I'm informing you of my decision.
这是个糟糕的主意
This is a bad idea.
他要参与这个案子了  无论如何
He's gonna investigate this case, no matter what!
这样  我们就相当于有绳子拴住他
So this way, we keep him on a short leash,
能控制住他了
we control him.
我听得到呢  老大
Uh, I'm standing right here, Cap.
迈克作为顾问
Mike will consult.
只负责观察
He'll observe.
就这么办
That's it.
现在  你们有什么发现
Now, what do you got?
据传言  制造那批子弹的军火商
Picked up chatter. The dealer we think customed
准备再做一笔交易
those rounds, he's making another sale.
布克·格拉西
Booker Grassie.
你还跟他说了其他机密吗
You share any other confidential information?
什么  我没有  这些还是他告诉我的
What? Not me. He's the one that told me.
我猜我的古董技巧还是管点用的
Guess my old tricks still work a little bit.
你就是个累赘
You're a distraction.
看吧  这就是我说的团队合作
You see that? That's what I like, teamwork.
真是合作无间
Already a beautiful relationship.
这段视频  被推测是枪手所传
The video, presumed to be posted by the shooter...
伙计们  这是迈克尔 劳瑞警探
Guys. This is Detective Michael Lowrey.
他将以顾问的身份加入我们
He'll be joining us as an adviser only.
警察还没有抓住嫌犯
Police have no suspects.
凶手依然逍遥法外
And the shooter is still at lar...
很高兴见到你们
Nice to meet you all as well.
-很高兴看到你已经没事了  -赞
- Thrilled to see you've had... - Sweet.
我现在好很多了  谢谢你们
I am much better now. Thank you.
我非常抱歉
I am so sorry about that.
-你看起来气色不错  迈克尔  -听着
- You look good, Michael. - Uh, look,
她一般叫我的全名
she calls me by my whole government name,
不过  你们叫我迈克就行
but everybody... You can just do Mike.
-当然  迈克  -收到  迈克
- For sure, Mike. - Got it, Mike.
好的  迈克尔
Yeah, sure thing, Michael.
你就是那个独立特行的角色
Ah, so you're that guy.
总会有个这样的人
Hey, there's always one.
的确  但现在不是了
Yeah. Right up till there's not.
这话什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
查尔斯  这可是迈克·劳瑞
Charles, it's Mike Lowrey, okay?
-低调点  就这一次  -上车
- Be cool. For once. - Let's load up!
我们要一起行动了
Think I might be able to hang out with you guys after all.
不是那个  我们坐这辆小龙虾
Nah, nah, that ain't the one. We're taking The Crawdaddy.
先进来看看吧
Wait until you see the inside.
-要帮忙吗老人家  -一边凉快去  小子
- You need any help, Gramps? - Go ahead somewhere, boy.
看看  这故作帅气的样子
Gee, trying to be all cool and shit.
大家也太严肃了吧
Okay, everybody is way too serious.
突击检查其实很有意思的
Raids are supposed to be fun.
像带枪郊游一样
They're like field trips with guns.
这不是突击检查  是现场监视
This is not a raid. It's surveillance.
监视  对
Surveillance? Right.
就是我们眼睁睁地看着犯罪实施
Meaning we're just gonna watch the crime.
我们会记录交易过程
We'll record him in the deal
然后带他回来审问
and bring him in facing serious time.
我们会让他开口
Then we'll get him to talk
他会告诉我们的
and he's gonna tell us everything
想知道的一切
that we need to know.
或者  既然他去那里  我们也去那里
Or since he's gonna be there and we're gonna be there,
我们可以直接抓住他
I mean, we could just grab him.
感谢你的提议
Well, thank you for your input.
好吧
Okay.
听好
Listen up.
迈克尔身上取出来的子弹
Booker Grassie is the guy
就是布克·格拉西卖的
that sold the bullets we took out of Michael.
等下  你能不能
Hey, look, um, you think you could stop
别当着大家的面叫我迈克尔了
calling me Michael in front of everybody?
这是你的名字
It's your name.
好吧
Okay.
放松身体  清空大脑
Relax and clear your mind.
借助上帝的灵能
Use God's inspiration
用你的心灵浸润他人的灵魂
to bring people peace and tranquility
带给人们平和与安宁
by penetrating their souls with your heart.
我们到了
We're here.
抱歉  劳瑞先生
Excuse me, Mr. Lowrey.
-借过一下  -好的  兄弟
- Just need to get past, please. - Sure thing, buddy.
你是技术人员  对吧  这肌肉
Uh, you're the tech, huh? Jeez.
居然把你安排在车里工作
They just leave you in the van?
对  我在这里更自在
Yeah, I'm more, uh... More comfortable in here.
明白了
Got it.
-放出老巴里  -你不是老巴里吗
- Sending in Big Barry. - You're not Big Barry?
《美国达人秀》的一名参赛歌手
我说的是监控无人机
He's our, uh, surveillance drone.
原来你们放的是无人机
Ah, so you send the drone in.
飞吧
Let's fly.
估计只有巴里才能享受得到乐趣了
I guess Barry gets to have all the fun.
在那里  黑色皮卡车
There. Black pickup truck.
-H-77的帮派成员  -这些人是谁
- That's our H-77 Boyz. - Who are they?
这些人绝对都是从外城来的
These guys are definitely from out of town.
想来争地盘
Trying to step up.
调广角  看全貌
I need wide angle, whole deal.
放大
Zoom in.
布克要卖他们一箱5.7乘28毫米的子弹
Booker's hooking them up with a crate of 5.7-by-28s.
-那就是布克·格拉西  -我们的目标
- That's Booker Grassie. - There's our deal.
开音频
Audio.
在这了
Here it is.
这东西能给你想要的
These will put a hole through anyone
任何目标上开个孔
and anything you point your gun at.
-我的货有保障  -他就在这  丽塔
- I guarantee my product. - He's right there, Rita.
-我们可以抓他  -不行
- We can grab him. - No.
我才不要冒不必要的风险
I'm not risking the collateral damage.
-我们动身吧  -我们等着
- Let's move. - Let's wait.
-你是头儿  -对  我知道
- You're the boss. - Yeah, I know.
-我刚说过  -我只是确认一下
- That's what I just said. - I just confirmed it.
好
Okay
你们以前是一对儿吧
You two used to date, right?
-差不多  -并没有
- Sort of. - Not really.
先看货款
Need to see the cash.
-看货款  -等下
- See the cash. - Wait.
后退  这里  这个人
Back. Go back. Right there. That guy.
-什么  -我要先看到钱
- What? - I need to see it.
包是空的
The bag is empty.
包里没东西  这是陷阱
There's no money in the bag. It's a rip.
我先看你的货
I need to see yours.
他们要杀了  这是陷阱
They're gonna kill... It's a rip.
-迈克尔  -布克不能死
- Michael. - We need Booker alive!
迈克尔回来
Michael, get back here!
妈的  凯莉  去  去啊
Shit. Kelly, go. Go!
打开摄像头
Get me body cams.
迈克尔不要动手
Michael, do not engage
我们要等队里所有人到位
until we have the rest of the team in position.
我们能不能点钱了  还是怎么
Can we count the cash, or what?
歌不错  调大声点
This is a nice song. Put it louder.
就现在
Now!
枪放下  枪放下
Put it down! Put it down!
能听到吗
Can you hear me?
帮我准备掩体
I'm gonna need you to lay me down some cover.
我们去你那边
We're coming to you.
好了  想活命  跟紧我
All right. You wanna live, you stay with me.
敢捣乱  我杀了你
Fuck with me and I'm gonna kill you.
数三下就过去
Coming at you on three.
开车  抓住卖子弹的
Bring the truck! Grab the merch!
一  二  三
One, two, three.
妈的
Shit.
妈的  布克
Shit. Hey. Hey. Booker.
布克  看着我  别死
Booker, look at me. Hey. Hey. Don't die.
赫斯塔尔P90  谁是买家
P90 Herstals. P90 Herstals, who's the buyer?
妈的
Oh, shit.
-布克  布克  -迈克尔
- Hey, hey. Booker. Booker. - Michael?
快叫救护车来  叫急救人员
Hey, get an ambulance in here now. Get the paramedics.
-布克  布克  -迈克尔
- Booker. Booker. - Uh, Michael.
你没听清吗  快叫他们
Don't you hear me clear? Just bring them in.
冷静
Calm down.
就听我这一次  行不行
Hey, just do what I ask you for once, please!
他死了
He's dead!
这是迪亚哥还是他的双胞胎兄弟
Is that Diego or his twin?
对  对  他的双胞胎兄弟
Yeah, yeah, his twin.
-卡梅丽塔  -别  别  别
- Carmelita. - Oh, no, no, no.
-谁啊  -马库斯  是我  卡弗·雷米
- Who this? - Yo, Marcus, it's Carver Remy.
我现在在忙  好吧
Look here, I'm busy, all right?
别浪费我时间  卡弗  别来烦我
Don't waste my time, Carver. Leave me alone.
别啊  老兄  事关重大
Come on, man. It's important.
看好我的小宝贝
Keep an eye on my baby.
-马库斯  -我退休了
- Marcus. - I'm retired.
现在我只和一种老鼠[告密者]说话
Only rats I talk to
就是在我家地下室里的
are in my basement.
-卡梅莉塔杀错人了  -妈的
- Carmelita shot the wrong twin! - Oh, shit.
听着  枪击迈克的那人  他要来杀我了
Listen, the guy who shot Mike, he's trying to kill me.
-什么  -我说真的
- What? - I'm serious.
一个骑黑摩托的人一直在跟踪我
A guy on a black bike's been tracking me.
就新闻上那个  就是他
The one on the news. It's him.
-鬼扯  -马库斯  我会骗你吗
- Bullshit. - Marcus, would I lie to you?
会  所以我们不和你这种骗子线人合作了
Yes. That's why we stopped using your ass as a CI.
-我告诉你  就是那人  -你找我干嘛
- I'm telling you, it's him. - What do you want from me?
保护性监禁  我不想死
Protective custody. To not die.
求你了  老兄  用我当饵  当什么都行
Please, man. Use me as bait, whatever.
你要抓这人吧  他找我来了
You want this guy? He's coming for me.
-你和迈克说过了吗  -刚打给你
- You talk to Mike? - I called you.
迈阿密十九世公寓  三层  我等你
Nineteenth and Miami. Third floor. I'll be waiting.
怂包
打给我
快打911
打不通电话
接电话啊
你个大傻逼
我说什么来着  我说什么来着
What did I say? No, no. What did I say?
我说了顾问  我说了观察
I said consult. I said observe. I...
看看这  一团糟  这是屠杀
Look at this... This mess. It's carnage!
这不是我一个人干的  他们自相残杀
I didn't do all this shit. They did this to each other.
等等  等等  你没杀任何人吗
Wait, wait, wait. You didn't shoot anybody?
-别这样  你明知道我朝人开枪了  -对
- Oh, come on, Cap. You know I shot some people. - Yeah.
他们都已经开枪了
Look, they had already started.
上帝  迈克  你答应过的
Ah, Jesus. Mike, you promised.
-不对  我没答应  -你答应了
- No, no, I didn't promise. - You promised.
-我说我会好好想象  -对
- I said I could picture you... - Yeah.
你站在个小树枝上  是个胖子
...on a limb, fat as hell,
下面就是鲨鱼之类的危险存在
with sharks and some shit.
对  这就是承诺
Right. That's a promise.
我们来这只是监视
We were here to watch.
怎样  是啊  我是监视了
What? Yeah, and I saw.
长官  看
All right, Cap, look.
包是空的  对吧  没钱
The bag is empty, all right? No cash.
那人举起手  擦擦鼻子
The guy reached up and scratched his nose.
我发现包轻飘飘的
I saw it had no weight to it.
-真厉害  长官  -这句我喜欢
- That's very impressive, sir. - Yeah. See, I like that one.
如果我没进来  格拉西肯定会死
If I hadn't come in, Grassie was a dead man for sure.
那确实  因为那人现在就在裹尸袋里
That's a relief, because your guy's in a body bag
-都死透了  -长官
- and he sure looks dead. - Cap. Ah...
干得不错  小迈迈
Good job, Mikey.
小伙子  说真的
Hey, look. Young boy, seriously.
我告诉你
Let me tell you something.
你应该本分点当个小孩  明白吗
You need stay in a child's place, all right?
少说什么该不该的  老爷爷  又没人问你
Spare me the street knowledge, grandpa. Nobody asked you.
不能因为我操了你妈
Look, just because I fucked your mother
-我就成你爷爷了  -操我妈
- don't make me your grandpa? - Fucked my mother?
-对  -够了  够了
-Yeah. - That's enough. That's enough.
-闭嘴  行吗  -你惹毛我了
- Stop. All right? - You got me fucked up.
-老不死的  -走了  走吧
- Old ass. - Stand down! Let's go.
-最好赶紧走  -走吧
- You better go on. - Let's go.
我他妈的要给你一脚  为民除害
I will knock your ass clean the fuck out.
-踢啊  来  -我成什么了
- Knock me out. Hit me. - What am I,
幼儿园老师吗  行了  走吧
a nursery school teacher? Come on, let's go!
妈的  我今天闲着呢
Shit. I got time today.
冷静  走吧
Cool down. Keep walking.
-借过  先生  -去吧
- Excuse me, sir. - Go ahead, man.
-你们要不要  -不用  去吧
- Do you guys want a...? - No, go.
去别处呆着吧
Just go ahead somewhere.
怎么了
What?
怂包
干嘛  怂包
What, quitter?
真他妈让人难受
This is some sad shit.
你的车哪去了
Where the hell is your ride?
女人们开去水疗了
Girls took it to the spa.
你还好吧
You all right?
不错  你还好吧
I'm fine. You all right?
再好不过了
Never felt better.
你可以
I mean, you could,
你要不考虑一下
if you wanted to,
开到最高时速
just do the speed limit.
你刚被丰田普锐斯超了
You let a Prius pass us.
这是什么
And what is that?
你把你的蛋蛋收在这吗
What, you got your balls tucked up in there?
知道吗  我不管哪一个蛋蛋
Hey. You know what? Neither one of my balls
都不想和你个傻蛋坐在这里
wanna be here with your stupid ass.
你居然带着小马库斯做凶杀调查
You brought Little Marcus on a murder investigation?
我会把他放在水疗
We're dropping him at the spa.
把他放在水疗
Dropping him off at the spa?
卡弗吓坏了  他等不了  兄弟
Carver is scared. He is not gonna wait, man.
顺路而已  迈克
It's on the way, Mike.
杀我的那个人
And what's the person that shot me
为什么要找卡弗·雷米这种小贼
want with a snitch like Carver Remy anyway?
我正带你去找原因啊  混蛋
I'm taking you to find out, motherfucker.
对不起  小马库斯
Sorry about that, Little Marcus.
外公不该这样说脏话
Pop-pop shouldn't be swearing like that.
但和迈克·劳瑞这种人打交道时
Only when you're dealing with people like Mike Lowrey,
你他妈的别无选择
you got no fucking choice.
抱歉  我又说脏话了
Sorry. There I go again.
-把宝宝带进去  -我不进去
- Take the baby in. - Oh, I ain't going in there.
那你也别想找出是谁要杀你
Then you ain't gonna find out who tried to kill you.
如果我进去  我现在就知道谁要杀了我
See, if I go in there, I know who's gonna kill me.
-特蕾莎·博纳特  -别废话
- Theresa Burnett. - Stop fucking around.
带上宝宝  进去
Take your baby. Go in there.
迈克  卡弗很害怕
Mike, Carver's scared.
他可等不了多久
He ain't gonna wait all day.
好吧
All right.
算你狠
不是吧  迈克  迈克
Uh-uh. No. Mike! Mike!
告诉马库斯我要杀了他
Tell Marcus I'm gonna kill him!
快走  快走
Go, go!
-快快快  -她怎么了  追来了吗
- Go, go, go! - What'd she do? Is she coming?
-快走  -天哪  她追来了
- Go,go! - She's coming! Oh, shit!
迈克  你认识特蕾莎很久了
Mike, you known Theresa a long time.
你觉得她到底有多生气
How pissed would you say she was?
-什么意思  比如1到10级  -对  10就像
- What you mean? Like, one to 10? - Yeah, 10 being...
就像我把你妹妹甩了这样的事情
Like when I broke up with your sister?
不  那是我生气的10级
No. That was me at a 10.
你这会儿干嘛提这个
Why would you bring that up right now?
好吧  我就是想
All right. I'm just trying to...
不  特蕾莎生气的10级是
No, a Theresa 10 would be...
就像上次你把星冰乐泼在我的法拉利上
Me that time you spilled Frappuccino in my Ferrari.
对对  就像这样
Yeah, yeah, that's it. That's it.
那她差不多有9级吧
Uh, she's probably like a nine, then.
9级
A nine? Oh, sh...
完犊子
Oh, shit.
现在是10级了
Better make it a 10.
忘记把宝宝湿巾给她了
Forgot to give her the baby wipes.
悲剧
Oh, tragedy.
你干嘛停下来
Are you stopping?
兄弟  那只是黄灯
Dude, that was a yellow light.
拜托  我们在赶时间
We are in a hurry. Come on...
怎么  怕被人看到不好意思吗
Oh, what? You embarrassed to be seen like this?
迈克·劳瑞就在这
We got Mike Lowrey here!
迈克·劳瑞在这辆日产贵士车里
Mike Lowrey in a Nissan Quest!
根本没人在乎  迈克
Nobody gives a shit, Mike.
他是我的优步司机
He's... He's my Uber driver!
类似国内滴滴司机
打击犯罪最主要的是
A big part of fighting crime
要抢在罪犯之前
is being ahead of the criminals.
我们不该停下来等那群鸽子
You don't have to stop for pigeons.
你只需要往前开  它们会飞走的
You just drive up to them. They'll fly away.
那最好是保险柜
That better be a safe...
或是钢琴
or a piano.
-这是我老婆的车  -那是卡弗·雷米
- This is my wife's car! - And that's fucking Carver Remy!
你怎么知道那是卡弗·雷米
You don't know that's Carver Remy.
他可以是任何人
That could be anybody.
-守住前门  -我已经退休了
- Cover the front door! - I'm retired!
我只是个老百姓
I'm a civilian!
这是个信号
This is a sign.
这是上帝给我们的信号
It's a sign from God.
特蕾莎来电
完蛋
Oh, shoot.
她知道了
She knows.
她什么都知道
She always knows.
紧急模式
布罗德摩尔旅馆这里需要救护车
I need 315 at the Broadmoor Hotel.
美国使用奔驰315监护型救护车
妈的
Fuck!
上帝  我知道之前请求过你帮助迈克
God, I know I asked you to help Mike out before...
但他现在已经快被打残了
but he's really getting his ass whupped.
上帝啊  再给我个信号吧
Lord, give me a sign.
你到底在干嘛  迈克
What the hell are you doing? Mike!
妈的
Shit!
你还好吗
You okay?
特蕾莎看到这破车的时候我肯定比你好
I'm better than you gonna be when Theresa see this car.
我抓到他了
他就在那里
妈妈 我不明白
阿曼多
Armando
是他结束了你父亲的生命
一击毙命对这家伙来说太仁慈了
必须要先折磨他
然后他才能死
你明白了吗
明白了
传球  传球  投篮
Pass it! Pass it! Head a goal!
投篮  卡莉
Head a goal, Callie!
打到她们想踢足球为止
Make them wanna play soccer!
-真累人啊  迈克  -可不是嘛
- Get down, Mike. - Yeah, I know.
不对
No!
如果她弄你  你也弄回她
If she fouls you, you foul her back!
对  对
Yes! Yeah.
有个佛教徒  对吧
So there's this... This Buddhist guy, right?
就是高山上的僧人
And, uh, you know, mountain man, way up high,
正沿着蜿蜒的山路走下山
going down this long winding road.
接着不知道从哪里冒出一个人
And out of nowhere, this other guy
骑着一匹马迎面上山
is riding a horse right toward him.
我觉得他也是个佛教徒
He's Buddhist too, I think.
老实说  我也不确定
Actually, I'm not sure.
就假设两人都是佛教徒吧
Just let them both be Buddhist, Cap.
好  那骑在马上的这个人
Okay, fine. So the guy on the horse
朝着这位下山的僧人飞奔而来
is riding toward our guy so fast
导致他必须得赶紧避让
that our guy's gotta get out of the way,
来避免被马撞倒
so as not to be trampled by the horse.
这个人浑身沾满泥土站起来说道
And the guy gets up, all dusty, and he goes:
嘿  你他妈要去哪里
"Hey, where the fuck are you going?"
骑在马上的人说
And our guy on the horse, he says:
"我不知道
"I don't know!
你得问这匹马"
Ask the horse!"
问马
Ask the horse? Huh.
正是
Exactly.
太棒了
Yes! Yes!
看你那副表情
See that face...? That. That?
就是这副
That's it.
和我一样的表情
That was my face.
故事里的马代表
The horse represents
我们所有的恐惧和创伤
all of our fears and traumas.
它以每小时100迈的速度带着我们乱跑
And it's got us running around a hundred miles an hour,
让我们连最简单的问题都答不出来
to the point where we can't even answer a simple question.
这个问题就是"我们要去哪里"
"Where are you going?"
你要去哪里  迈克
Where are you going, Mike?
不  卡莉
No, Callie!
不要传球
Don't pass!
直接投篮
Shooters shoot!
咱家的基因就不适合打篮球
Kid's got the family curse.
迈克
Mike...
你必须要掌控你自己的人生
you gotta get control of your life.
你必须要勒住缰绳
You gotta grab the reins
在你的马带你摔下悬崖之前
before your horse runs you off a cliff.
一起吃饭吧  卡莉见到你会很高兴的
Come over for dinner. Callie would love to see you.
我会再给你读个佛教故事
I'll read you a Buddhist story.
我有本故事书
I got a book full of them.
等等  还是你做饭吗
Wait, you gonna be cooking again?
是啊
Hell, yeah.
好吧  我们还是点披萨吃吧
All right. We'll order pizza.
那就最好了
Yeah, I think I can do that.
中了
Bingo.
-老大  -我不知道  快走快走
-Cap! -I don't know! Go, go, go!
开枪打他
Get him.
我可以帮忙  需要做什么
I can help. What does he need?
-开枪  -闭嘴
- Shoot. - Cállate.
-射穿那女的  -不  走开  走开
-Through the bitch. - No, move, move.
-到车后面去  -我可以帮忙
- Get behind the car. - I can help.
走开  到车后面去
Move! Get behind the car!
你怎么回事
What's wrong with you, man?
你明明可以打到他的
You had that shot.
不打无辜的人
No innocents.
你是不是疯了
You crazy, man, you know that?
请求救护车  枪击  有警员中枪
Three-fifteen. Shots fired. Officer down.
何塞·马蒂公园
Jose Marti Park.
我们需要空中应急支援
We need Air-One on a three.
我是探员迈克·劳瑞
This is Detective Mike Lowrey.
警长中枪倒下了
The captain is down.
预备
Ready!
瞄准  开枪
Aim! Fire!
预备  瞄准  开枪
Ready! Aim! Fire!
你是对的
You were right, man.
你说过如果我去复仇
You said if I went out there,
会害死无辜的人
I was gonna get somebody killed.
最后一票
One last time?
One last time.
妈妈 其他人都死了 是时候了吧
是的 杀了他
但是杀他之前 看着他的眼睛
替我告诉他
告诉他什么 妈妈
我发现了一份关于布克的可疑财务报告
I ran a suspicious financial report on Booker.
他所有的公司都是同一个会计师
All his LLC fronts have the same accountant.
注册会计师皮坎特·詹金斯
Picante Jenkins, CPA.
那你只需要见一个皮坎特就行
Yep. You don't meet too many Picantes.
所以我们只要敲门然后问话就行
So we just gonna do a knock-and-talk?
对
Yeah.
哇  那些都是什么
Whoa! What the hell is all that?
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
迈克  你不需要榴弹发射器
Mike, you don't need a grenade launcher.
是的  但是我想要一个
Yeah, but I want one.
他只是个会计师  迈克
He's an accountant, Mike.
迈克  我们不能像之前那样进去
Look, Mike, we're not going in there like that.
-像哪样  -一直以来
- Like what? - Hey, look, all our lives,
我们都是坏男孩  对吧
we've been bad boys, all right?
现在是时候成为好男人了
Now it's time to be good men.
到底谁会愿意唱那首歌
Who in the hell wanna sing that song?
♪ 好男人  好男人  你要怎么办 ♪
♪ Good men, good men What you gonna do? ♪
也许你认真点唱
Well, maybe if you sang the song
这首歌就能朗朗上口了
like you meant it, it'd catch on.
不要
No.
敲门  问话
Knock and talk.
好  敲敲
Yeah. Knock, knock.
-迈克 迈克  -迈阿密警察  趴下
- Mike! Mike! - Miami PD! Get down!
趴下
Get down!
-迈克  -你在干什么
- What is happening? - Mike!
说好的敲门问话呢
What happened to knock and talk?
你把我的门弄坏了  你把门弄坏了
Hey, you broke my door. You broke my door!
先生  对不起  行吗
Sir, sorry about the door, okay?
一点大猩猩牌万能胶就能修好
A little Gorilla Glue will make that just fine.
美国一种万能胶水品牌
-你们有搜查令吗  -我要求你立刻跪下
- Hey, where's your warrant? - I need you on your knees
双手放在后脑勺上
with your hands behind your head right now!
先生  如果你还不停地乱动
Sir, if you keep moving,
我就要射爆你的头
I'm gonna shoot you in your face.
-不  他不会开枪的  -不  我会开枪的
- No, he's not. - Yes, I am!
迈克  他是会计师  只需要和他谈谈就行
Mike, the man is an accountant. We just need to talk to him.
所以你想和这个
So you wanna have a conversation
吸嗨了的橙色大山谈话
with a coked-out orange mountain?
这是最新的数据
Here's the latest figures.
交给我处理  行吗  你退后就可以
Look, let me handle this, okay? Just back up.
我将用我的心浸润[插入]他的灵魂
I'm gonna penetrate this man's soul with my heart.
什么鬼
What?
是的
Yeah.
看好学着点儿
Watch and learn.
舔屁狗
Hey! Hey, ass licker.
让我给你来个拳交吧
I'm gonna fast-food fist-fuck you.
先生  这也太变态了吧
Sir, that's just nasty.
我知道我们现在让你很为难
Now, I recognize that this is a difficult situation.
-别过来  -别过去  马库斯
- Don't come over here. - Don't go over there, Marcus.
我们只需要你的客户收据
We just need your client's receipts.
-什么  -布克·格拉西
- What? - Booker Grassie.
请问你有任何记录
Any record of...? Unh!
你觉得有多深入他的灵魂啊
Hey. How deep you think you got in his soul?
有时候为了做正确的事得受点苦
Sometime you gotta suffer for what is right.
是不是该轮到另一边脸了啊
Don't you turn that other cheek.
-放开我  -好吧
- Get off me! - All right.
先生  我知道你很害怕
Now, sir, I realize that you're scared.
我们都有害怕的时候  有时候恐惧
Hell, we all scared. You know, sometimes fear just...
现在你觉得如何
So, what you thinking?
我觉得该轮到你来处理了
I think you should handle this one.
我也这么觉得
Yeah, me too.
形象大使出局  该来点儿硬料了
MLK just tapped out. You got Brother Malcolm now.
我们可以采取任何必要的手段来处理此事
We can handle this by any means necessary.
我认识你  你就是那个被枪击的条子
I recognize you. You're that cop that got shot.
运气衰到家了啊
Bad year you're having, Butterscotch.
如果你没有那把枪和警徽
If you didn't have that gun and badge,
我能把你生吞了
I'd fucking eat you.
这是唯一能阻止你生吞我的东西吗
This the only thing that's keeping you from eating me?
是啊
Yeah.
来吧  大个子
Bring it, big boy.
-左侧安全  -铐上他
- Left line clear! - Cuff him.
你们在这里干什么
What the hell are y'all doing here?
我把他们叫过来的
I called them.
什么  说好的坏男孩最后一票呢
What? What happened to bad boys one last time?
这是最后一票啊
This is one last time.
只是重新创作一下  迈克
But this here's the remix, Mike.
我们现在和弹丸小队合作了
We work with AMMO now.
现在搞这一套了是吧
That's that shit, okay?
在我咬断它之前你还有三秒钟
You got three seconds before I bite it off.
把你该死的手指从我脸上拿开
Get your damn finger out my face.
说说吧  法官  检察官  线人
So tell us. Judge, prosecutor, criminal informant,
老大  还有你  你们有什么共同点
the captain, and you. Who do you have in common?
数以百计的调查  行动
Hundreds of investigations, operations...
847起案件
Eight hundred and forty-seven cases
交错于受害者之间
in the nexus of the victims.
那上面谁想杀你
Well, who up there wants to kill you?
-谁不想啊  -行了
- Hell, who doesn't? - All right.
这些还只是罪犯
That just the criminals that we're looking at.
我不相信有人不想杀他
I don't trust a person that don't wanna kill him.
把我的名字也放上面吧
Hell, put my name up there.
行了  真谢谢你啊
Thanks. Got it. Appreciate it.
你从会计那发现了什么吗
What you get out of the accountant?
他的记录一团糟
His records are a mess.
可不是嘛
Surprising.
但我成功地进入了他的钥匙链
But I did manage to get into his Keychain.
-所以呢  -我进入了他的所有社交媒体
- So? - All of his social.
满眼屌图
Looking at a lot of dick pics
却没啥线索
but not so many clues.
进行面部识别过滤这些照片
Facial rec for anyone in our system.
收到
On it.
这是我被枪击前三天拍的
That's three days before I got hit.
回到上一张  带链子的那个人
Hey, go back to that last shot. The chain.
放大
Yeah, zoom in.
拽罗
Zway-Lo.
-拽罗是谁  -洛伦佐·罗德里格斯
- Who's Zway-Lo? - Lorenzo Rodriguez.
绰号拽罗
Goes by Zway-Lo.
在他成为街头混混之前
Used to coach him in peewee hoops
我教过他打篮球
before he went for that thug shit.
很好的球员  但我不得不让他在
Great player, but I had to bench him
冠军赛上坐冷板凳
during the championship.
你让一个10岁的孩子在冠军赛上做冷板凳
You benched a 10-year-old in the championship?
是啊  那小混蛋叫我傻逼
Yeah. Little fucker called me a dickhead.
-你们至少赢了吧  -当然没有
- Did y'all win at least? - Hell, no.
他是我们的明星球员
He was our star player.
我们输了40分  但我表明了我的立场
We lost by 40, but I made my point.
团队合作不能瞎搞
Okay, there's no "I" in "team."
傻逼倒是可以
There is one in "dickhead" though.
闭嘴  听着  拽罗喜欢毒品和武器
Man, shut up. Look, Zway-Lo's into drugs, weapons.
他是塔戈林的副手之一
He's one of Taglin's lieutenants.
但塔戈林在迈克中枪当晚被发现死亡
Taglin was found dead the same night Mike got shot.
我猜他现在是别人的副手了
I guess he's someone else's lieutenant now.
洛伦佐·罗德里格斯
Lorenzo Rodriguez.
没有抵押  连银行账户都没有
No mortgage, not even a bank account.
但明天是他的生日
But it is his birthday tomorrow.
如果要庆祝
If he's celebrating,
他这样的人只能去三个地方
there's three spots for a cat like that.
迪图  冰冻45号  亿万
Ditto, Ice 45, Zillion.
你能查一下这些俱乐部的记录吗
Can you get into their club records?
冰冻45号真该加强他们的网络安全了
Pfft, Ice 45 should really up their cyber security.
好了  冰冻45号
Okay. Ice 45.
迪图  亿万
Ditto. Zillion.
那里  罗德里格斯
There. Rodriguez.
派对在今晚
The party's tonight.
就在亿万
Zillion it is.
好了  晚上11点在夜店碰头
All right, we meet at the club at 2300,
便衣任务  好好打扮一下
UC, so wear your Sunday best.
这是抓捕  进去出来  没有伤亡
This is a grab. We're in. We're out. No bodies.
这次严格规定为非致命突袭
This raid is strictly nonlethal.
非致命
Nonlethal.
有人通知过坏人吗
Has anyone informed the bad guys?
橡胶子弹  相信我你会喜欢的
ACLU rounds. Rubber. Trust me, you'll enjoy them.
你想射多少就射多少
You get to shoot as much as you want.
♪ 坏男孩  坏男孩 ♪
♪ Bad boys, bad boys ♪
-别  -♪ 你要怎么办 ♪
- Oh, hell, no. - ♪ Whatcha gonna do? ♪
♪ 你要怎么办  当我 ♪
♪ Whatcha gonna do When we come...? ♪
-不  -不  别
- No, uh-uh. - No! No!
别  你们再也不准唱这首歌
Never. Y'all will never do that again.
是啊  你们还瞎唱歌词
Yeah, and you fucking up the lyrics,
我们好久才练出来的好吗
which take a long time to learn.
-别再唱了  -行咯
- Don't do that. - All right.
-不  别再唱了  -认真的
- No. Don't do that. - Seriously.
-好好好  -对不起咯
- Okay. - Sorry, sorry.
-这么小气  -不会再唱了
- Shit. - Won't happen again.
找你们自己的歌去
Get your own damn song.
你敢相信吗
You believe that shit?
蠢货
Dumbass.
随便了  伙计
Whatever, man.
懒得理你
Miss me with that bullshit.
我来吧
I got this.
你好  女士们  乔治在名单录里吗
Hello there, ladies. Uh, Georgio in there tonight?
-完全没听说过  -请到后面排队
- No idea who that is, sir. - The line's in the back.
妮可  佩吉
Nicole! Paige!
你们真漂亮
You guys look so good.
-谢谢  -如此美丽  天啊
- Thank you. So beautiful. - Oh, my God.
那是我的迈克尔叔叔
That's my Uncle Michael,
那是他的朋友  马库斯叔叔
and that's his pal, Uncle Marcus.
介意他们进来吗  他刚离婚
You mind if they come in? He just got divorced.
-太可怜了  -是啊
- Oh, that is so sad. - Mm, yeah.
-进来吧  进来吧  -来吧
- Come on in. Come on in. - Come on.
-别来  -来吧
- Oh, hell, no. - Come on, kids. Let's go.
-来吧  -不
- Uh, yeah. - Oh, no.
-是的  -不
- No, yeah. - Uh-uh.
-这是真的  -不  一点也不
- It's real. - No, not at all.
-真的  -不
- Yeah. - No, sir.
-假的  -真的
- Uh-uh. - Yeah.
凯莉  目标在哪
Kelly, what's the target QTH?
第二层  贵宾平台
Second level. VIP platform.
-我看到了  -在上面
- I have eyes on. - Up top.
你好啊  宝贝
Hi, baby.
目标确认
Target confirmed.
贵宾平台只有一条路进出
Platform is one way in, one way out.
我们把他逼到绝路了
We got him cornered.
他旁边手下有把点55口径手枪
Man on his two-side has a 55, hot.
实施A计划
Stay with the A-plan.
凯莉  你解决拽罗保镖
Kelly, you're on Zway-Lo's bodyguard.
收到
Copy.
迈克  你觉她那样吊着怎么打碟的
Mike, how you think she DJ like that?
她臀部肌肉一定很强壮
She must got some strong ass muscles.
听着  我跟你摊牌了  迈克
Look, I'm gonna be honest with you, Mike.
我很久没做爱了
I ain't had sex in a long time.
是啊  太久了  我已经开始胡思乱想了
Yeah, too long. Too long. I be thinking of shit.
-很危险的想法  迈克  -马库斯
- Crazy shit, Mike. - Marcus.
我感觉自己被囚禁了
I feel like I'm locked up since...
马库斯  你知道他们能听见吗
Hey, Marcus, you know they can hear you?
太吵了  他们听不见我们说话的
It's too loud. They can't hear us.
他们听不见我们说话
They can't hear us.
听着  听着  有时候我上网
Look, look, sometime I go to the Internet,
我看到一些很奇怪的东西
and I see some weird shit on there.
-我看过有个男的把他的  -马库斯
- I saw a man put his... - Marcus.
-马库斯  -怎么了
- Marcus. - What?
我们能听到你说话
We can hear you.
开个玩笑
That's a little jokey joke.
你们都没听到吧
Y'all didn't hear that, did you?
-就位  -准备好了
- In position. - Setting up.
迈克  马库斯  平台见
Mike, Marcus, meet you at the top.
迈克和马库斯移动中  右边楼梯
Mike and Marcus moving, stairs right.
丽塔移动中  左边楼梯
Rita on the move, stairs left.
-大家就位了吗  -就位
- Everybody in position? - Set.
这裙子真漂亮  姑娘
That dress is incredible, girl.
-很有风度  -你好啊
- You got style. - Oh, hi.
-谢谢  -没问题
- Thank you. - Yeah.
待命  待命
Stand by. Stand by. Stand by.
我不行  我跟闺蜜一起来的
I can't. I'm here with my girlfriends.
她们一起来我也不介意  宝贝
Mm, they can come too, baby.
今晚不行
Ah, I can't tonight.
把他蛋蛋踢爆  该行动了
Knee him in his balls, and let's go.
-得土安来的  -得土安来的
- From Tétouan. Mwah. - From Tétouan.
-再见  宝贝  -再见  宝贝
- Bye, baby. Ha, ha! - Bye, baby.
她为什么要穿成这样
Why'd she wear that?
那可不是便衣任务该穿的衣服
That is not a undercover dress.
你该穿点  更便衣一点的
You should've wore something... undercover.
生日快乐
Happy birthday.
各位
Yo, yo, yo, everybody!
大家嗨起来
Let's make some noise!
我们有个特别的客人  今天是他的生日
We got a special guest in the house! It's his birthday!
祝他生日快乐
Let's wish him a birthday on one!
三  二  一
Three, two, one.
生日快乐
Happy birthday!
我们爱你  拽罗
We love you, Zway-Lo!
-拽罗  拽罗  -世界之巅  宝贝
- Zway-Lo! Zway-Lo! - Top of the world, baby!
生日快乐  傻逼
Happy birthday, dickhead.
你今天要去坐牢了  混蛋
Yeah! You going to jail, motherfucker.
我说"罪犯"  你说"监狱"
When I say "criminal," you say "jail."
罪犯  监狱
Criminal. Jail.
迈阿密警局  不准动
Miami PD! Freeze.
好身手啊
Damn!
我告诉过你他是个运动员
I told you he was an athlete.
-我们得跳下去  -我才不跳
- We gotta jump. - I'm not jumping.
-他要跑了  快跳  -该死
- He's getting away! Jump now! - Shit!
拽罗
Zway-Lo!
给我让开
Get out of the way!
我需要辆车
I need this. I need it.
-不好意思  -你要干什么
- Excuse me, sir. Excuse me. - What you doing?
-等等  -警察在办案
- Hey, hold on! - Official police business.
-那是我的车  -说了是警察办案
- That's my car! - This is the police.
后退
Back up!
-你在搞什么鬼  -快来
- What the fuck? - Come on!
你他妈走楼梯下来
It is of no advantage for me
我刚那一跳就没任何卵意义了
to jump off the fucking thing if you take the stairs!
我跟你说了我才不跳
I told your ass I wasn't jumping!
拽罗在二号街左转了
Zway-Lo turned left on 2nd Ave.
-还系安全带了呢  -是的
- Putting your seat belt on? - Yeah.
-我们现在走这风格了是吧  -没错
- That's how we do it now? - You're damn right.
这些条子在紧跟着我
Number one's on my ass!
穿过395州际公路到上城区
Crossing 395 into Overtown.
迈克  不能去上城区
Whoa, Mike. Overtown's a no-go.
拽罗的手下在那里  他们很危险
Zway got people here. Dangerous people.
我们才是危险人物
We're dangerous people.
这该死的枪  狗屎橡胶子弹
Damn Nerf gun, rubber bullet bullshit.
他们在射子弹  我们在射小熊软糖
They shooting slugs, we firing gummy bears.
麦克  麻烦你靠边停车一下
Mike, pull over for a minute.
我得告诉你一件事
I need to tell you something.
-你叫我靠边停车  -没错
- Pull over? - Yeah.
那让我看看拽罗会不会停车
One second. Let me see if Zway will pull over.
拽罗  马库斯要停一下车
Zway-Lo! Marcus needs to pull over for a second!
我们能不能暂停一会
Hey, can we get a time-out?
他妈的  迈克  我真的得告诉你一件事
Damn it, Mike, I need to tell you something!
-什么事  -我跟上帝保证过
- What? - I made a promise to God.
-跟谁  -上帝啊
- To who? - To God.
你他妈在胡说什么
What the hell are you talking about?
听着  我跟上帝说如果你挺过来
Look, I told the Lord that if you made it through
我就不会再使用暴力
that I would make no more violence.
他很清楚你是在胡说八道
He definitely knew you was bullshitting with that.
暴力是咱俩的专长
Violence is what we do.
我是指更深一层  迈克
It's about your soul, Mike.
我们的职责是保护人民  服务群众
Our job is to protect and serve.
你说的很对
You're damn right.
我现在要给这个混蛋服务一下了
I'm about to serve this bitch right now.
瞧瞧这玩意儿
Oh, look at that!
靠
Damn! Oh!
他看起来像大象人了
That is some Elephant Man shit right there.
你看到没
Yo, you see that? Oh!
-看到了  -好了  够了
- Yeah, I see it. - Hey, stop it.
-它在呼唤我  -什么  离远点
- It's calling me, Mike. - What? Leave it...
控制不住  但它真的在呼唤我
I can't help it, but it's calling me.
别闹了  你有毛病吧
Stop it. What the hell is wrong with you?
别动它
Just leave it alone.
真的别动
Yo, leave it alone.
别动  马库斯
Leave... Marcus.
-你会把这玩意戳破的  -那真够恶心的
- You're gonna pop that shit! - That shit nasty!
说了让你离远点
Then leave it alone.
靠
Damn. Oh...
别动了  我们该
Just leave it alone! Let's...
再让我试一次  就一次
One more time. One more again.
上城区的人要来了  快走
Overtown is waking up. Let's go.
弹丸小队你们在哪
AMMO, where you at?
我们堵车了
Got jammed up.
现在正在进入上城区
Hitting Overtown now.
穿好装备
Gear up.
来吧
Come on.
操
Fuck!
我们手上有你们的人
We got your man!
我会杀了他
I'll kill his ass!
住手  醒醒  拽罗
Stop it! Wake up, Zway-Lo!
快醒醒  快他妈的给我醒醒
Wake up! Wake up! Wake your ass up!
伯内特教练
Coach Burnett?
傻逼
Dickhead.
还觉得我是傻逼吗
Still think I'm a dickhead?
拽罗  是谁想杀我
Zway-Lo, who wants to kill me?
操  所有人都想杀了你
Shit, everybody wanna kill you.
对吧  我告诉过你了  迈克
Yeah, I told you, Mike.
别管我 杀了他们
他在说什么
What's he saying?
杀了他们
他到底在说什么
What's he saying?
-你俩今晚死定了  -他们来了
- Y'all both dying tonight. - Coming up.
妈的
Oh, shit.
谢天谢地
Thank you, God!
你怎么让他逃走了
Why'd you let him get away?!
火力压制
Lay suppression fire!
-靠  -快上车
- Oh, shit! - Get in!
-车上有比特犬  -快上车
- There's a pit bull! - Hey, come on!
你想被狗咬还是吃枪子
Wanna get bit, you wanna get shot?
快上车  我们走
Come on! Let's go!
-我靠  -你怎么了
- Oh, shit. - What you got?
这里就像臭白人的地下室一样
It's like an angry white man's basement in here.
-靠  他妈的手榴弹  -拔了它
- Shit, a fucking grenade. - Pull it.
-快拔啊  -我们又不是在打越战
-Pull it! - This ain't fucking Vietnam!
-那你就拿着吧  -去你的  迈克
- Hang on to it, then. - Damn you, Mike!
快看看  老兄  还有什么
Ahh! Come on, man! What else you got?
噢  真棒
Ahh! Oh, yeah!
-快开枪啊  -不  不要  迈克
- Shoot that shit! - No, no, Mike!
我向上帝发过誓  不再用暴力了
I made a promise to God! No more violence.
那你以为谁给你的这武器
Who do you think sent you that weapon?
-我不知道  -那是上帝给你的枪
- I don't know! - That is God's gun!
-真的吗  -在你最需要的时候送来的
- It is?! - Sent in your time of need.
靠  我现在真的很需要
Well, shit! I do need it now!
没错  你是上帝的小帮手
Yes. You are a vessel for the Lord's work.
我是小帮手  就好像大卫打败巨人歌利亚
Yeah, I'm a vessel. Like David and Goliath.
对  大卫有他的弹弓
Yeah, David with the slingshot.
是的  现在这就是你的弹弓
Yes! That is your slingshot!
快去消灭你的敌人们
To smite thine enemies!
你知道吗  我们就像圣经的坏男孩  宝贝
You know what? Bad boys of the Bible, baby!
-没错  阿门  -阿门
- Exactly! Amen? - Amen? Amen! Amen!
-妈的  -你的眼镜呢
- Shit! - Where are your glasses?
-我不需要戴眼镜  -你什么都没打中
- I don't need no damn glasses! - You ain't hitting shit!
我们走
Let's go!
你打越野车  我打后面的6个
Get that ATV! I got the six! Oh!
棒呆了
Yes!
不
No!
迈克  你他妈在干什么
Mike! Mike! Mike! What the hell you doing?!
上帝啊  我不想就这么死了
Oh! Lord, I don't wanna die this way!
-迈克  -靠
- Mike! - Oh, shit!
-我的  我的错  -当然是你的错
- My bad, my bad. - Damn right, that's your bad!
迈克  迈克
Mike! Mike!
走开
给我让开
Get out of the fucking way!
只有死亡才能将我们分离.
Haste el fuego.
多恩  我需要你
Hey, Dorn. I need you.
嗨  听着
Hey, hey, look.
我遇过这种事  很多次
I been there before. Many times.
不会有事的
It's gonna be all right.
那是拽罗的手机  你能黑得进去吗
That's Zway-Lo's phone. Can you break it?
当然  我要找什么
Yeah. What am I looking for?
我得知道他跟谁谈过  通话纪录
Who he's talking to. Call logs.
还有我要你稍微快点  好么
And I'm gonna need you to hurry up just a little bit.
好吧  但这操作会有点不那么合法
Okay, but I'm gonna have to go on the dark side.
好吧  你做得来吗
All right. You good with that?
当然
Yeah.
那就开始吧
Yeah. Yeah. Let's do it.
多恩  他是个大块头
Dorn, he's a big guy.
他怎么会在这方面这么在行
How'd he get so good at this stuff?
-哪方面  -计算机之类的
- What stuff? - Tech shit.
-他看起来像个杀手  -是  他当过保镖
- He looks like a killer. - Is. Used to be a bouncer.
有天晚上  看到有个家伙在骚扰女人
Guy one night was getting physical with a woman...
然后大个子就失控了  揍了那家伙
Yeah, big man lost it. Hit him.
-那个混蛋被打死了  -从此他就不打架了
- Bastard dropped dead. - Avoided the fight ever since.
搞定了
Here we go.
给我上两个月的纪录
Give me the last two months.
墨西哥
Mexico.
你到底想找什么
What are you after here?
我要你给每个号码都发条消息
All right. To each one of those numbers,
"只有死亡才能将我们分离"
I need you to text the phrase, "Hasta el fuego."
信息发送成功
搞定了
Done.
好了  让我来吧   谢了
All right. I got it. Thank you.
-你确定  -我来吧  走吧
- You sure? - I got it. Go.
国际监狱资料库
搜索  圣塔玛利监狱
认证中
连接到圣塔玛利监狱
搜寻囚犯  伊莎贝艾瑞塔
1995年11月11日遭到逮捕
发色  棕色   眼珠  咖啡色
姓名  伊莎贝尔·艾瑞塔
1996年3月20日产子
未知号码  你好  麦克
我们被终止了
We're shut down.
-什么  -终止是什么意思
- What? - What do you mean, shut down?
弹丸小队要被解散了
AMMO's done.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
一切都会没事的
Look, everything's gonna be all right.
相信我  好吗
Trust me on this, okay?
一切都会没事的
Everything's gonna be all right.
迈克
Mike.
你还好吗
You all right?
我觉得他是我儿子
I think he's my son.
什么
What?
24年前  在我们当搭档之前
Twenty-four years ago, before we partnered up, um...
霍华德局长从警校把我选出来
Captain Howard pulled me right out of the academy.
没人知道我是谁
Uh, nobody knew who I was.
他派我到阿莉塔斯贩毒集团做卧底
He sent me in undercover with the Aretas cartel.
索伦森
Sorenson.
韦伯
Weber.
瓦嘉斯  卡弗
Vargas. Carver.
这些受害者当时全是办这案子的人
All of the victims were on that case.
这是复仇
This is revenge.
迈克  但你没办那起案子
Yeah, Mike, but you weren't on that case.
我的名字不在上面而已
My name wasn't on it.
我卧底得很深
That's how deep I was.
我当时叫瑞奇·罗伦斯
I was Ricky Rollins.
贝尼托·阿雷塔斯
Benito Aretas.
他死了  他没在追杀你
He's dead, Mike. He ain't after you.
不是他
Not him.
是他妻子
His wife.
伊莎贝尔
Isabel.
我是她的司机
I was her driver.
我们越走越近
We connected so... deep.
我们无所不谈  她教会我一切
We talked about everything. She showed me the whole game.
怎么走路  说话  打扮
How to walk it, how to talk it, put clothes on it.
是她造就了迈克·劳瑞
She made Mike Lowrey.
我们相爱了
We fell in love. Heh.
也就是说你曾经
Are you telling me the one time that you...?
伊莎贝尔·艾瑞塔
Isabel Aretas.
当时
The one time.
很快警察们都全出动了
Takedown was coming.
缉毒局  烟酒枪炮爆炸物管理局  所有人
DEA, ATF, everybody.
我准备直接抛弃这次行动
And I was gonna ghost the whole operation.
和伊莎贝尔一起私奔
Me and Isabel were gonna run away with each other.
那你怎么改变主意了
What made you change your mind?
他们叫她La Bruja[西语]
They call her La Bruja.
女巫
The Witch.
她喜欢搞一些黑暗的东西
She is into some dark shit.
死神
Santa Muerte.
那个女人
That woman
是个冷血的杀手
was a stone-cold killer.
所以我只能让这个我爱的女人
So I had to put the woman I love
下半辈子都在牢里度过
behind bars for the rest of her life.
从那以后  我还是选择做回警察
Chose the badge, and I've been choosing it ever since.
迈克  你是操了一个已婚的女巫吗
Mike, you fucked a married witch?
我跟你说了那么多  就只听了这个吗
So all the shit I just said, and that was your takeaway?
信息量太大  我得消化一下
No, it's just a lot to digest.
我以为我很了解你  没想到
You think you know somebody and...
难怪你穿衣风格
Well, hell, now it explains
那么像毒贩
why you dress like a drug dealer.
你到底要不要听我讲
So you wanna hear this shit or you don't?
对不起  但是你怎么知道那是你儿子
Sorry. But you don't know that's your son, Mike.
你不清楚那女巫有没有跟别人上过床
You don't know who that witch was fucking.
贝尼托·阿雷塔斯没有生育能力
Benito Aretas couldn't have kids.
伊莎贝尔是被捕后八个月
Isabel gave birth in prison
在监狱里生下了这孩子
eight months after her arrest.
"只有死亡才能将我们分离"
"Hasta el fuego."
这是他对我说的话
He said that to me
在我从直升机上跳下来之前
before I jumped from the chopper.
这句话是我和伊莎贝尔编的
Me and Isabel made that up.
根本都不是真正的西班牙语
It's not even real Spanish.
这只是我俩之间的情话
It's some shit we said to each other.
意思是  只有死亡能将我们分离
It meant like, "We'll be together until we burn."
那个叛徒要来了
准备好
没问题
我们走吧
不是吧  迈克
Nah, Mike.
马库斯  他年龄也对得上
Marcus, he's the right age.
他像我一样疯疯癫癫
He's crazy like me.
像我一样冷酷无情
He's ruthless like me.
像我一样无所畏惧
He's fearless like me.
他就是堕落版的我
He's the fucked-up me.
不是的  迈克
No, Mike.
你才是堕落版的自己
You the fucked-up you.
你这是在妄下结论好吗
You jumping to conclusions. All right?
事情终将会水落石出的
Shit's gonna work itself out.
你得有点信心
You gotta trust that.
好吧
Yeah...
你说的没错
You're right.
兄弟
Oh, man.
我爱你  兄弟
I love you, man.
我也爱你
我得走了
I gotta go.
迈克
Mike.
先生  让我过去一下
Let me get past you there, sir.
抱歉  不好意思
Sorry there. Excuse me.
不好意思
Excuse me.
塞这里正好
That's the right spot for me right there.
不好意思  先生
Oh, excuse me, sir.
我的位子就在那儿
Seat right there.
让我过去一下
Let me get by you.
小心你的脚趾
Watch your toes
小心脚趾
Watch your toes there.
终于  好了
It's all right. There you go.
不行  马库斯
No, Marcus.
我不会让你独自去执行自杀式任务
I'm not letting you go on a suicide mission alone, Mike.
这是我的事
This is on me.
我不想因为我的事
I'm not letting anybody else get killed
而让无辜的人丢了性命
dealing with my shit.
迈克  她可是个女巫
Mike, she's a bruja.
她能让你的眼珠子融化进你的榆木脑子里
She'll make your eyes melt into your stupid-ass head.
还能让你的鸡巴掉下来
She'll make your dick fall off.
我是说阴茎
I meant penis.
再说了这也不关你事
You should be minding your own business anyway.
马库斯  请你回家吧
Marcus, please go home.
我们要一起飞  还要一起死
We fly together. We die together.
什么
What?
不是
Oh, no.
这是我们的黑话
That's just something we say.
什么事都没有
It's all good. It ain't...
我好像是让你们有点
Oh, I can see how that got y'all a little...
你们来自哪的
Uh, where y'all from? Where you from?
你见到他之后打算怎么办
So, what you gonna do when you see him?
你真准备把你亲儿子送进监狱里吗
You really gonna put your son behind bars?
不  我要杀了他
No. I'm gonna kill him.
杀了他
Kill him?
你真的要杀自己的亲儿子吗  迈克
You really gonna kill your own son, Mike?
我他妈还要把他装到裹尸袋里
I'm gonna put him in a fucking bag.
你介意我们换个位子吗
You mind if we switch seats?
太好了  谢谢
Yeah, please.
不好意思
Excuse me.
你知道你这样做会下地狱的
You realize you will go to hell?
我不相信有地狱  马库斯
I don't believe in hell, Marcus.
但是地狱相信你的存在
Well, it believes in you.
我意思是  杀你自己的亲儿子
I mean, killing your own son.
等待你的会是一片将你吞没的黑暗
Brother, that's a darkness that swallows you whole.
可能我已经被吞没了
Well, maybe I already been swallowed.
我死过一次  还记得吗
I died, remember?
我要去结束这一切
I'm ending this shit, man.
我早该知道他是你儿子了
I should have known he was your son.
因为他胖揍你的时候  迈克
Because the way he whupped your ass, Mike.
跟你简直一个饼样
That was a ass-whupping straight from thy own loins.
超凡脱俗
A supernatural ass-whupping.
我能做他的教父吗
Can I be the godfather?
你想知道你能做什么吗  马库斯
You know what you can be, Marcus?
什么
What?
闭嘴
Quiet.
我该闭嘴是吧
Oh, I should be quiet?
没错
Yeah.
你和一个女巫有了一个男巫宝宝
All right, you just had a warlock baby with La Bruja
这宝宝要杀你  可能还要杀我
who's trying to kill your ass, probably mine too,
还要吸我们的血什么的
sucking our blood and all of that shit,
但是我应该保持沉默
but I should be quiet.
是的呢  好吧  迈克
Yeah. Yeah, okay, Mike.
你操了个女巫竟然不戴套
How you fuck a witch without a condom?
这屁事就是你一手造成的
You wrap that shit up, man.
兄弟  换个座位吧
Hey, my man. We need to change seats.
好的
Yep. Okay.
墨西哥城
我是迈克  我是马库斯
Mike, Marcus.
有了这些装备就跟在迈阿密一样
This makes us even for Miami.
未知号码  你好  迈克
未知号码  6:30分在伊达尔戈宫见
该干活了
Yo, we hot.
你又叫他们了
You called them again.
是丽塔先打电话给我的
Hey, Rita called me.
-兄弟们最近怎么样  -嗨
- What's up, fellas? - Hey.
你们好呀
Hey. Hey.
你好
Hola.
有他们在感觉好多了
I feel better when they're here.
我也这么觉得
Yeah, me too.
你们这些玩具都是哪里弄来的
Whoa, where'd you get all the toys?
库尔纳瓦卡的缉毒局
DEA station in Cuernavaca.
我们抓人  他们拿功劳
We capture her, they take the credit.
我们要是死了  也和他们一点关系都没有
Get ourselves killed, they've got nothing to do with it.
都听我说
All eyes on me.
我来当诱饵  在伊达尔戈宫碰头
I'm the bait. We meet at Hidalgo Palace.
是一家城外的废旧酒店
It's an old hotel outside the city.
我会一直和她讲话  直到你们发现枪手
I'll keep her talking till you guys spot the shooter.
要是她直接开枪打你呢
What if she just shoots you?
不会的  她会跟我谈谈的
Nah, she's gonna wanna talk.
我们有一些  故事
We, uh... have history.
抄家伙  抓他们
Okay. Snatch and grab. We get them,
然后天亮之前飞回家
and we're on a plane to the States by dawn.
多恩  给我看看楼层卫星图像
Dorn, get me a floor-plan satellite image.
我们的摄像头分布在楼外
We'll have eyes on the outside and...
和楼内
on the inside.
大家都别碰枪手  他是我的人
Hey. Nobody touches the shooter. He's mine.
没错  的确是
Uh, yes, he is.
今天咱要干点疯狂的事了呢
You, uh, coloring a little bit outside the lines today, huh?
别死了
Don't die.
你也要保证我们俩都能回家
You make sure we both come home.
没发现任何威胁  正在监测建筑内部
No identifiable threats. Monitoring channels inside.
同时干扰外部信号
Jamming everything outside in case
以免被反监测
they're running countersurveillance.
不可能就她一个人在里面
No way she's here alone.
这可是个集团  她的后援绝对不少
It's the cartel. She's gonna have serious backup.
马库斯正在从后包抄
Marcus is moving towards the back.
马库斯  我们会从上空掩护你
Marcus, we're covering your position from the sky.
什么都没发现
Still nothing.
正在靠近
Moving in closer.
你好  瑞奇
Hola, Ricky.
还是说我应该叫你迈克
你好  伊莎贝尔
Hola, Isabel.
不够尽兴呢
以前你可是很喜欢抚摸我的呢
我要亲手杀了她
I'm gonna kill her myself.
算了吧
Keep it.
他在哪里
Where is he?
这里以前是我们的地盘
我曾经要过你的命
但是你活下来了
可能是我把你塑造得如此强壮
又或者
是死神另有安排
我们注定要再见对方一次
这他妈跟演电视剧一样
This is some real telenovela shit.
这些我都处理好了
他妈的
Shit!
什么信号都没了
I just lost all comms.
-操  弹丸小队  -马库斯  回来
- Fuck. Ammo? - Marcus, come in.
操蛋  他们在干扰我们
Shit. They're jamming us.
他们知道我们在这里  真操蛋
They know that we're here. This is fucked.
我没法重新连接
I can't get back in.
巴里宝贝不在受干扰的范围内
Still got Baby Barry on an outside frequency.
现在就只剩下我俩了
你为什么不告诉我  我有个儿子
告诉你又怎么样
照顾他
就像你这样照顾我吗
这本会是个惊喜
It was gonna be a surprise.
如果我们当初一起私奔的话
After we ran away.
有动静
I'm seeing tactical movement.
有二三十个人正组成一个包围圈
Twenty to 30 threats forming a perimeter.
我们得走了
We gotta go.
-出入口都在哪  -这里
- All points of entry? - Here.
这里的冷气流可能是洗衣房的排气口
That cold airflow could be a laundry exhaust.
你怎么能这样对待我们的儿子
How could you do this to our son?
是我的儿子
My son.
他知道我是谁吗
Who does he think I am?
当然知道你是谁
Exactly who you are:
懦夫  叛徒
The coward, the traitor...
别这样
Don't do this.
往前走  警探
Keep it moving, detective.
看到了吗
You see that?
放下武器
Drop it.
我们走
Let's go!
你想干什么
What you gonna do?
只有死亡才能将我们分离
Hasta el fuego.
别什么苏爱果  那是火  对吧
No "el suego." That means fire, right?
-闭嘴  -不  别凯什么特
- Cállate. - No, no "cate."
你跟这男人得谈谈
You and this man need to talk.
-这可是能改变人生的事  -闭上你的嘴
- It's life-changing shit. - Shut the fuck up.
-枪别抵得那么用力  -马库斯  放松
- Easy on the barrel! Easy! - Marcus, relax.
不要  迈克
No. Mike,
就是缺乏沟通才成这样
it's lack of communication that got this shit fucked up.
他要告诉你点事  你会不喜欢听
He needs to tell you something. You ain't gonna like it,
但你还是得听听
but you need to hear it.
该死
Oh, shit!
迈克  他们要去搭直升机
Yo, Mike, they're moving up to the chopper!
马库斯
Marcus!
-把你眼镜戴上  -你搞什么飞机
- Put your glasses on! - What the hell was that?
你也太不会扔了
That was a bad throw!
迈克  小心了
Yo, Mike, careful!
眼镜这事你还真说对了
You were right about the glasses.
这事我都跟你说了几年了
I been telling your ass that shit for years.
妈的  像切换到高清了
Shit, this is like HD!
走  走  快走
Go! Go! Go!
12点方向有敌人
Contact! Twelve o'clock!
走  快点走
Go! Go, go, go!
伊莎贝尔和枪手上楼了
Hey, Isabel and the shooter went up the stairs.
你们能掩护我们吗
Can you cover us?
-凯莉  右翼  -收到
- Kelly! Flank right! - Copy!
-拉菲  左翼进攻  -收到
- Rafe, pan left! Push! - Copy that!
-多恩  跟着拉菲  -好
- Dorn, follow Rafe! - Yup!
大家伙
Hey, big man.
你得打伤几个人
I'm gonna need you to hurt some people.
心理治疗我出钱  行吗
I'll pay for therapy, all right?
我真会需要的  不开玩笑
I'm gonna need it. Seriously.
-我说到做到  -我走中间
- Yeah, I got you. - I'll hold the middle.
-你们就直取楼梯  -直取楼梯
- You push hard for the stairs. - Push hard for the stairs.
没错
Yeah.
你们真不错  警督
Hey. It's good shit, lieutenant.
你也是  警探
You too, detective.
看来你也没蠢到掉渣
You ain't such a dumbass after all.
听我指令
On me!
上
Go!
变身
Transition!
快走
Go!
妈的
Shit.
开枪  打死他们两个
Shoot! Take them both!
那边  就在那边
Right there, right there!
他们哪弄来的这些直升机
Where the hell they getting all these helicopters?
迈克
Mike!
-打飞行员  -打旋翼
- Take out the pilot! - Take out the rotor!
-你瞄哪里啊  -飞行员
- What are you aiming at?! - The pilot!
瞄旋翼  你要是打了飞行员
Aim at the rotor! If you shoot the pilot...
打中了
Got him!
要命了
Oh, shit!
妈的  你这家子人都太狠了  迈克
Shit. You got a fucked-up family, Mike.
建筑要倒了  我们得走了
The building's coming down! We gotta move!
迈克  马库斯
Mike! Marcus!
妈的
Shit.
跪下  伊莎贝尔  跪下
On your knees, Isabel. Get down.
迈克
Mike!
你这臭女人就当得个教训吧
Let that be a lesson to your witch ass.
阿曼多
Armando...
你是我儿
you're my son.
You're my son.
我不想打
I don't wanna fight.
别起来
Stay down.
我叫你别起来
I said, stay down.
我之前不知道
I didn't know.
我要是知道
If I had known...
迈克  你搞什么名堂
Mike, what are you doing?
我要用我的心灵
I'm trying to penetrate his soul...
浸润他的灵魂
with my heart.
不
No.
不  迈克  别啊
No, Mike, no.
我那会儿在经历点事
I was going through something.
你是谁
Who are you?
我说了
I told you.
骗子
Liar.
最后一次机会
Last chance.
你是谁
Who are you?
问你妈
Ask your mother.
他说的是真的吗
无关紧要  于你而言他什么都不是
你们看见这火势没有
Hey, y'all see all this fuego?
-咱们能出去谈吗  -闭嘴
- Can we take this shit outside? - Cállate.
他是谁
-告诉他  -告诉他  他妈
- Tell him! - Tell him, mama.
他是我爸吗
他是不是我爸
Is he my father?!
是
Yes.
杀了他
Kill him.
-不  等下  等下  -该死
- No, no, wait, wait, wait... - Shit.
躺下  慢慢躺下
Lay down. Down. Down.
妈的
Oh, shit.
迈克  我们得走了
Mike, we gotta go.
迈克  该走了  快点
Mike! Gotta move! Now!
迈克  我们得走了
Mike! We gotta go!
拽住我  拽住我
Hold me! Hold me!
妈的
Oh, shit!
迈克  别松手  别松手  天啊
Mike! Don't let me go! Don't let me go! Oh, shit!
坚持住  我拉着你
Hold on. I got you.
迈克  我过不来
Mike! I can't get to you!
我坚持不住了
I can't hold on.
拉我上去  我不想这么死
Pull me up! Mike, I don't wanna die this way!
迈克  我在往下滑
Oh, Mike, I'm slipping.
快点
Come on!
快点  我觉得我的屁股要熟了
Hurry! I can feel my ass cooking!
加把劲
Come on.
快点  我们该走了
Let's go! We gotta move!
胸部上方枪伤  我们需要医生
Gunshot wound, upper chest! We need medical!
-来了  -没事的
- En route! - All right.
-没事的  我来吧  -放他下来
- It's okay, I got it. - Put him down.
-我们需要外伤敷料  -好了
- We need a trauma dressing. - Right.
放松
Relax.
我没法保证一切都会好的
I can't promise you it's gonna be all good...
毕竟你做了那么些事  但是
after all the stuff you've done, but...
我能保证  我一定会陪着你的  好吗
I can promise you I'm gonna be there, all right?
你好啊
Hey.
我是你马库斯叔叔
I'm your Uncle Marcus.
不过我们之后再聊这个吧
But we'll talk about that later.
恭喜丽塔
对  没错
Yeah, yeah.
对  对
Yeah, yeah. Yeah.
放下吧
There we go.
-好了  -天啊
- All right. - Oh, my God.
你们真是的
You guys.
-蛋糕来了  -好了  现在
- There it is. - Yes. Now...
是时候一起举杯
it's time to raise your glasses...
-敬我们的新局长  -敬我们的新局长
- to our new captain. - To our new captain.
我妈跟你问好
Hey, my mom says hey.
你是不打算让我忘了这茬了吧
Oh, you're not gonna let me live that down.
大伙们  我有事要跟你们说
Oh, and, guys, I got some news for you.
我开始做心理治疗了
I just started therapy.
我的治疗师觉得要是我们能一起去
My therapist thought it'd be beneficial
做个小组治疗  会很有效果
if maybe we could hit up a group sesh together.
-超有意思的  -当然了
- It's super sick. - Oh, for sure.
-一定的  -我们会去的
- Definitely. - Yeah, we will be there.
-马库斯  我跟你私下聊两句  -好
- Marcus, let me holler at you for a second. - Yeah.
让我考虑一下
Uh, let me think about it.
-他要我们去做治疗  -我才不去
- He wants us to go to therapy. - Yeah, I'm not going.
我才不去
Ha, I'm not going.
老兄  听着
Hey, man, look, um...
我们也不互相说这种话
You know, we don't say this kind of shit to each other,
不过
man, but just...
谢谢
thank you.
迈克  你不用谢我的
Mike, you don't have to thank me.
如果你想退休
If you wanna retire,
你要知道  我不会来阻止你的
just know that I am not gonna try to stop you.
你挣来的
You earned it.
我也会百分之百支持你
And I will support you 100,
不管发生什么
no matter what.
但你忘了一件事
But you're forgetting one thing.
-我们说好一辈子  -一辈子
- We said for life. - For life, baby.
-我侄子来了  -没错
- There's my nephew. - Yes.
小马库斯刚醒了
Hey. Little Marcus just woke up.
好了  第一件事
Okay, first things first.
给你个小惊喜
Little surprise for you.
马里恩温泉度假区三日游
Three days at the Marion Springs Resort.
就当是给被我破坏的按摩日
You know, kind of a little apology
一点小小的歉意
for the spa day I crashed.
没错  专心放松  亲爱的
Yes, a little quality time, baby.
-专心休息  -知道了  亲爱的
- Quality time. - Yeah, baby,
但是梅根和雷吉去度蜜月了
but Megan and Reggie are on their honeymoon.
这周末我来带孩子
Oh, I got the baby this weekend.
我和我的弹丸小队小队
Me and my AMMO squad.
你和特蕾莎去就行了  好好玩玩
You and Theresa go ahead, have fun.
你还有蓝色小药丸吧
You still got them blue pills, right?
伟哥
我才不需要什么蓝色小药丸
I don't need no damn blue pills.
你就是这么说眼镜的
That's what you said about your glasses.
迈克  你抱着宝宝还挺合适
That baby looks good on you, Mike.
你抱孩子确实还挺不错  迈克
You do look good holding a baby, Mike.
-你真这么觉得吗  -真的
- Yeah, you think? - I do.
你没问题了吧  迈克  我们走吧
You good, Mike? Let's go, team.
-好  -等下  这不
- Yep. - Wait, nothing...
等下  你在说什么呢
Wait, no. Whatcha talking about now?
我们不是说一起带孩子的吗
We said we were doing this together.
不行  我还得工作
Oh, no, I have to work.
我明天再来看看你
I'll check on you tomorrow.
-我给你带酒  -丽塔  别闹了  别
- I'll bring wine. - Rita, stop playing. Hey, no.
你们都同意一起留下带孩子的
Y'all all agreed that we were all gonna stay with the baby.
我到车上去等你
I'm gonna see you be in the car.
-给我妈发短信  -这不好笑  别
- Just text my mom. - Oh, okay, that's not fun... No.
好了  乖  乖乖
Okay. All right, all right. Shh.
♪ 坏男孩  坏男孩 ♪
Hey. ♪ Bad boys, bad boys ♪
♪ 你要怎么办 ♪
♪ Whatcha gonna do? ♪
♪ 等我们来找你  你要怎么办 ♪
♪ Whatcha gonna do when we come for you? ♪
不  我们不能这么对下一代人
No. No, we not doing that with the next generation.
-你得唱对了  -行吧
- Just you gotta sing it right, man. - All right.
♪ 坏男孩  坏男孩 ♪
♪ Bad boys, bad boys ♪
♪ 你要怎么办 ♪
♪ Whatcha gonna do? ♪
♪ 等我们来找你  你要怎么办 ♪
♪ Whatcha gonna do When we come for you? ♪
我走了
I'm gone.
绝地战警3
疾速追击
你怎么样
How you doing?
我在还我的债
I'm paying my debt.
欠得不少
It's a big one.
或许已经有机会
Opportunity may have presented itself
能帮你减轻一点肩上的债
for you to pay down some of that debt.
感兴趣吗
You interested?
当然
Yeah, man.
你会不带套干一个女巫吗
Would you fuck a witch without a condom?
我才不会
I would not.
听到没  迈克
He would not, Mike.